music
音楽
applause
拍手
Our feast of knowledge tonight
今夜の知識の饗宴
Our monthly feast of knowledge
毎月の知識の饗宴
I am very happy to invite the director of our physics institute today
今日は私たちの物理学研究所の所長をお招きできることをとてもうれしく思います
Director Li Dingguo
李定國所長
He is also a Special Review Researcher of the Institute
同研究所の特別審査研究員でもある
Director Li was born in 1976
リー監督は1976年生まれ。
Ph.D. from Brown University
ブラウン大学博士号取得
He was also at Virginia Tech
彼はバージニア工科大学にもいた
after a while
交過一段時間
and then back to Taiwan
そしてまた台湾へ
He has been back to Taiwan for a long time
彼は久しぶりに台湾に戻ってきました
I believe everyone in academia knows him
学界の誰もが彼のことを知っていると思います
Also served in the hospital
病院でも提供されています
Executive Secretary of our Academic Association
私たちの学術協会の事務局長
This is an academic program within the Chancellery
これは首相官邸内の学術プログラムです
And review and so on
そしてレビューなど
at the National Science Council
国家科学会議で
which is now the Ministry of Science and Technology
現在の科学技術省です
He also served as the director of the Theory Center
理論センターの所長も務めた
Program host at the Nano Center, etc.
ナノセンター等でのプログラムホスト
That
それか
Dr. Li has also won the membership of the Physical Society of the Republic of China
李博士は中華民国物理学会の会員にもなりました。
Also a meeting of the British Physical Society
英国物理学会の会合でもある
Also a meeting of the American Physical Society
アメリカ物理学会の会合でもある
Needless to say, he has won numerous awards
言うまでもなく、数々の賞を受賞しています
We have the Outstanding Honor Award of Houjindui in China
中国の侯神堆の優秀栄誉賞を受賞しています
National Science Council Outstanding Research Award
米国学術会議優秀研究賞
And the Outstanding Talent Award from the Outstanding Talent Foundation, etc.
そして、Outstanding Talent FoundationよりOutstanding Talent Awardなどを受賞。
Then I always say that our basic science
それから私はいつも言っています、私たちの基礎科学は
To say that everyone knows
誰もが知っていると言うのは
is working very hard
とても頑張っています
But every time we look for a speaker
でも講演者を見つけるたびに
satisfies power
力を満たす
I believe
私は信じている
Although everyone read the topic today, it seems a bit
今日のトピックはみんな読んでるけど、ちょっと
Seeking to generate higher overheating
より高い過熱度の追求
Mechanism of superconducting temperature
超電導温度の仕組み
high temperature superconductivity
高温超伝導
I believe everyone has heard of this term
誰もがこの言葉を聞いたことがあると思います
he is trying to put
彼は置こうとしている
whole process mechanism
プロセス全体のメカニズム
to tell everyone
みんなに伝えるために
I think
私が思うに
We use these two hours
この2時間を使います
I believe
私は信じている
Director must
理所長一定
Let everyone know how this high-temperature superconductivity came about
この高温超伝導がどのようにして生まれたのかをみんなに教えてください
the future potential
将来の可能性
future
未来
this
これ
practical application
実用化
people say you can see
人々はあなたには見えると言います
He has already placed a resignation in front of this
彼はすでにこの問題を前に辞任を表明している
Our goal is to say
私たちの目標はこう言うことです
this resignation train
この辞任列車
Actually now
実は今
Already have how to take a step further
さらに一歩前進する方法をすでに持っています
I believe we will gain a lot tonight
今夜はたくさんのものを得ることができると信じています
We welcome Director Li
リー監督を歓迎します
Thank you Vice President Wang
王副社長に感謝します
Thank you all for coming to the party tonight
今夜パーティーに来てくれてありがとう
This is just now Vice President Wang also said that this is a big challenge
これは今、王副主席も「これは大きな課題だ」と言いました。
because it's me
それは私だから
first
第一次
to use
使用する
Talk about the superconducting mechanism in a popular speech
人気演説で超電導の仕組みについて語る
This is something that everyone may have heard of but may not know about superconductivity.
超伝導については誰もが聞いたことがあるかもしれませんが、知らないかもしれません。
The reason why I took this name was because of the magic I thought about this research topic is
私がこの名前を付けた理由は、この研究テーマについて私が考えた魔法のためです。
most interested have done
最も興味のある人はやった
decades of this
この何十年も
Superconducting
超電導
The problem is this is what I've been looking for
問題は、これが私が探していたものであるということです
an important direction
重要な方向性
Then today I may try to share with you why this topic is very
それでは今日は、このトピックがなぜ非常に重要なのかをお話したいと思います。
very interesting very challenging
とても興味深い とてもやりがいのある
So how can we gain some new understanding of physics
では、どうすれば物理学について新たな理解を得ることができるのでしょうか
So here's what I'm talking about today
それで今日私が話していることはここです
The main thing is to talk first, of course talk a little bit
大切なのは最初に話すことです、もちろん少しだけ話しましょう
What exactly is directed? What does it mean?
いったい何を指示されているのでしょうか?それは何を意味しますか?
It may be more than you imagine
それはあなたが想像している以上のものかもしれません
And a little more strange phenomenon
そして、もう少し奇妙な現象
with some of its mechanics is very simple
いくつかのメカニズムは非常にシンプルです
Why do we have so many strange phenomena
なぜこれほど奇妙な現象が起こるのか
But if you know something about this
しかし、これについて何か知っていれば、
you can imagine what it does
それが何をするか想像できます
You may hear more about this
これについてさらに詳しく聞くかもしれません
That is the aspect of the possible application of the steering material
それがステアリング素材の応用可能性の側面です
that's been done a lot
それはたくさん行われました
The other one, of course, is what Wang Fuyuan said just now.
もう一つは、もちろん、今、王福源が言ったことです。
The discovery of this high-temperature conductor
この高温導体の発見
Near the end of 1986
1986年末近く
almost 30 years now
もう30年近くになる
the discovery of this
これの発見
a lot of confusion
多くの混乱
that's confusing we're still trying to understand
それは混乱する、私たちはまだ理解しようとしているところだ
don't already have quite a few close
まだクローズがほとんどありません
To understand the cause of this problem
この問題の原因を理解するには
With the source of this tide island
この潮島の源流とは
Well we just discovered a lot
さて、私たちはたくさんのことを発見しました
It's not the same as the old tide island
昔の潮島とは違う
Then of course the next step is
そしてもちろん次のステップは
How to find higher tide temperature
より高い潮温を見つける方法
Then of course why seek this
それならもちろん、なぜこれを求めるのですか
I have quite a big idea with this
これについてはかなり大きなアイデアがある
OK, let's talk about this tide island phenomenon
さて、この潮島現象について話しましょう
Of course, the English name of this Superconductor is Superconductor
もちろん、この超電導体の英語名は Superconductor です。
Calling this name, of course, ordinary people will think of it as one.
この名前を呼べば、当然一般人はそれを思い浮かべるだろう。
This English conductor has several opinions
このイギリス人の指揮者はいくつかの意見を持っています
One is the conductor and the other is the length of the vehicle
1 つは車掌、もう 1 つは車両の長さです
If the conductor of the train is also called conductor
電車の車掌をコンダクターとも呼ぶ場合
The other one is the conductor, the conductor of the orchestra.
もう一人は指揮者、オーケストラの指揮者です。
Then this Super is of course Superman
そうすると、このスーパーはもちろんスーパーマンです
This Superconductor is what it means
この超電導体とはどういう意味ですか
Then there is another kind of Taiwan that everyone is more familiar with.
そして、誰もがよく知っている別の種類の台湾があります。
Well done called Semiconductor
半導体と呼ばれてよくやった
there is a comic
漫画があります
Let’s say this conductor only has work part time
この車掌はパートタイムしか仕事をしていないとしましょう
So it is semiconductor
つまり半導体です
Of course with SumSent is also right
もちろんSumSentでも大丈夫です
This semiconductor will see its resistance later
この半導体は後でその抵抗がわかります
part of it is like conducting
一部は指揮をしているようなものです
sometimes not like
好きじゃないこともある
So it is a general semiconductor
つまり一般的な半導体です
the name goes
名前が入ります
Then this superconductor
そうするとこの超電導体は
when he takes a good name
彼が良い名前をとったとき
Dangdang doesn't sound very familiar
ダンダンはあまり理解できないようです
what does super mean
スーパーってどういう意味ですか
what about this gentleman
この紳士はどうですか
is honest
正直です
this is dutch
これはオランダ語です
At the University of Leiden
ライデン大学にて
in 1911
1911年に
about 100 years ago
約100年前
In 1911, he conducted an experiment
1911年に彼はある実験を行った。
Of course he wasn't
もちろんそうではなかった
especially to find
特に見つけるために
This super early experiment
この超初期の実験は
this is a resistor
これは抵抗器です
let me explain
説明させてください
What does this resistor mean?
この抵抗器は何を意味するのでしょうか？
This is the resistance represented by the OMU
これは OMU で表される抵抗です
Its special experiment is that it can reduce the temperature to a very low
その特別な実験は、温度を非常に低い温度まで下げることができるということです。
It is a liquid state, but it turns into a liquid state at 4.2 degrees
液体状態ですが4.2度で液体状態になります
Above 4.2 degrees it is gaseous
4.2度以上ではガス状になります
It can make liquid damage
液体によるダメージを与える可能性がある
that is its most important job
それがその最も重要な仕事です
After this work it is done
この作業が終われば完成です
It puts some metals and other things in the low temperature to see
金属などを低温に置いて観察します。
what happened
どうしたの
This approach is often a scientific approach
このアプローチは多くの場合、科学的なアプローチです。
It's just going to a place that no one else has been to.
誰も行ったことのない場所に行くだけです。
See questions that people have never seen before
人々がこれまで見たことのない質問を見る
Of course the problem is the low temperature
もちろん問題は気温の低さです
Occurs at very low temperatures
非常に低い温度で発生する
Of course, low temperature is very important now.
もちろん、今は低温が非常に重要です。
This whole is under low temperature and it goes to measure
この全体を低温下で測定します
It this resistance of course from high temperature
もちろんこれは高温からの抵抗です
This 270 degrees can be 273 degrees
この 270 度は 273 度になる可能性があります
So this is about 269 degrees
これは約 269 度です
Just -269 degrees facility
ちょうどマイナス269度の施設
Zero degrees at our facility is
当施設では零度です
273 degrees absolute
絶対273度
This is the absolute temperature
これが絶対温度です
So you are now saying that from this room temperature all the way down
つまり、この室温からずっと下までそれを言っているのですね
You're going to get down to about 300 degrees
300度くらいまで下がります
you can get to this temperature
この温度まで上がることができます
Absolute temperature below 0 degrees is no temperature
絶対温度0度以下は温度ではない
This temperature has an absolute value
この温度には絶対値があります
is 0 degrees
0度です
it keeps cooling
冷え続けます
Then watch the resistor drop all the way down
次に、抵抗が完全に下がるのを観察します
to here
ここへ
suddenly fell fast
突然急に落ちた
down to 3 orders of magnitude 4 orders of magnitude
最小 3 桁 4 桁
Negatives from here to 10
ここから10までマイナス
fall here
ここに落ちる
then 4.15 degrees
それから4.15度
It can be seen here that 4.2 degrees
ここで 4.2 度であることがわかります。
just too high
ただ高すぎる
a little lower temperature
少し低い温度
So too high is very important
高すぎることは非常に重要です
put it in
中に入れて
it's lower
それは低いです
Eh
えー
it got
それは得た
this phenomenon
この現象
this is
これは
superconducting
超電導
found for the first time
初めて見つけた
This is 1911
これは 1911 年です
You will probably see this picture many times
この写真は何度も見ることになるでしょう
this is
これは
This temperature is called the part temperature Tc
この温度を部品温度 Tc と呼びます
C is
Cは
English is called Critical Temperature
英文叫Critical Temperature
is the part temperature
部品の温度です
The Tc I used in this talk is the representative
今回の講演で使用したTcが代表的です
just go from normal to super old temperature
常温から超高温まで
What we are looking for is to increase the temperature
私たちが求めているのは温度を上げることです
best to mention room temperature
室温と言うのが一番良いでしょう
this is everyone's dream
これはみんなの夢です
Of course it is asking why
もちろん理由を尋ねます
This zero resistance is of course here you see
このゼロ抵抗はもちろんここにあります。
Its resistance is not zero
その抵抗はゼロではない
It is also a real parent, a real mother
実の親でもあり、実の母でもある
Just good resistance
ちょうど良い抵抗力
not exactly zero
正確にはゼロではない
How do we know this is zero resistance
これが抵抗ゼロであることをどうやって知ることができるのでしょうか
After this material comes out
この資料が出てから
Of course it slowly started to become popular in cryogenics
もちろん、極低温学でも徐々に普及し始めました
so many people do
とても多くの人がそうします
it is
それはです
Then from just now what it does is mercury
それから今からそれは水銀です
is the arch
アーチです
then there is lead
それから鉛があります
These materials one by one
これらの材料をひとつひとつ
Then first do single-atom metals in the periodic table
次に、最初に周期表の単一原子金属を調べます。
Then do the bimetallic
あとはバイメタルをやります
alloy of two elements
2つの元素の合金
do it
やれ
do here almost
ほぼここでやります
almost
ほとんど
Then later do three elements
その後、3 つの要素を実行します
you can tell
教えてもいいよ
The physicist starts from the simplest kind of element
物理学者は最も単純な元素から始める
Then do two more elements
次に、さらに 2 つの要素を実行します
make three elements
3つの要素を作る
start looking for
探し始める
Say the superconducting temperature
超電導温度を言ってください
So doing here is actually the highest at that time
だからここでやるのが実は当時最高だったんだ
23 degrees
23度
I was doing a postdoc at the time
当時私はポスドクをしていました
I'll study this when I do
そうなったら勉強します
Why is the superconducting temperature 23 degrees?
超電導の温度はなぜ23度なのでしょうか？
Back then I called it a high temperature superconductor
当時はそれを高温超伝導体と呼んでいた
Of course it looks funny now
もちろん今見ても面白いですよ
That's only 23 degrees absolute temperature
それは絶対温度わずか23度です
At that time, this material was also difficult to make.
当時はこの素材も作るのが大変でした。
Only one group can make it
1つのグループだけがそれを達成できる
that is a world record
それは世界記録です
back then i remember in ganis
あの頃、私はガニスで覚えています
It is also written in the world record
その世界記録にはこうも書かれています
This is the world's highest temperature superconductor
これは世界最高温度の超伝導体です
23 degrees
23度
that's a big deal
それは大したことだ
then this is
それならこれは
After that, of course, new materials started to come out.
その後、もちろん新しい素材が出てきました。
but it's too late
でももう手遅れです
At that time in 1970
1970年の当時
At that time we were the earth
あの頃、僕らは地球だった
The material is also interesting
素材も面白いです
but at that time
しかしその時は
Everyone do this temperature
みんなこの温度でやってね
This was 4 years ago in 2011
これは4年前の2011年でした
This is a British magazine
これはイギリスの雑誌です
journal of physics
物理学雑誌
published a special issue
特別号を発行しました
100 Years of Drilling Development
掘削開発の100年
just said
今言いました
The words developed in the past 100 years
過去100年の間に発展した言葉
Of course there are some
もちろんいくつかあります
Nuo Biao said it was related to this drill
ヌオ・ピョウはこの訓練に関連していると述べた
In fact, the first person is of course
実は一人称はもちろん
It's that Mr. Ones just now
さっきのワンズさんだよ
campman
キャンプマン
Now at University Leiden
現在ライデン大学に在籍中
There is a Museum
博物館があります
If you go to University Leiden
ライデン大学に行くなら
that is very old
それはとても古いです
300+ Years of University
300年以上にわたる大学の歴史
There is a laboratory in that university
あの大学には研究室があります
There is this Museum
こんな博物館があります
dedicated to his cryogenic laboratory
彼の極低温研究室に専念
That is the most famous cryogenic laboratory in the world
それは世界で最も有名な極低温研究所です
He spoke with a promise
彼は約束を持って話した
In fact, it is not because of the discovery of the manipulation
実は改ざんが発覚したからではない
It's because he lowered the temperature to one too high
それは彼が温度を1度上げすぎたからです
this is
これは
Sorry I didn't translate
ごめんなさい、翻訳できませんでした
This is the original promise
これが本来の約束です
Citation when Community gave him a promise
コミュニティが彼に約束したときの引用
not about coaching
コーチングの話ではなく
Because at that time, I didn't understand manipulation at all.
当時は操作というものを全く理解していなかったので。
Back then there was no quantum physics
当時は量子物理学はありませんでした
I don't know what that means
それが何を意味するのか分かりません
wait a minute and you'll think about it
ちょっと待ってください、そうしたら考えてみましょう
so don't appreciate at all
だから全く感謝しない
And at that time, they were also speculating on the teacher's parents
そしてその時彼らは先生の両親について推測していました
Sifang shopkeeper is not a spirit
四方店主は精霊ではない
what's special
何が特別なのか
There are of course many explanations for this
もちろんこれには多くの説明があります
So this is probably when
だから、おそらくこれがそのときです
But in 1972 this paper
しかし、1972年にこの論文は
Of course it is a theoretical paper
もちろん理論論文です
explains the phenomenon of manipulation
操作の現象を説明する
This is written by water
これは水によって書かれたものです
after this comes out
これが出た後
The overall understanding of manipulation is greatly increased
操作に対する全体的な理解が大幅に向上します
That's an important theory
それは重要な理論です
a breakthrough theory
画期的な理論
So it's actually the same as the discovery of the God Particle
つまり、それは実際には神の粒子の発見に似ています
everything matters
すべてが重要
This theory has far-reaching
この理論は広範囲に及ぶ
Many developments in high-energy particle physics
高エネルギー素粒子物理学の多くの発展
the two
二つ
Even three of them are also physicists
そのうち3人も物理学者です
Same County NOW WebPly 1973
同じ郡の NOW WebPly 1973
I also saw some manipulative phenomena
操作的な現象も見ました
special phenomenon
特殊な現象
Of course I won't talk about this, just 90 points a piece
もちろんこれについては話しません、1作品90点だけです
One of the books that this gentleman gave is that he is doing a Ph.D.
この紳士がくれた本の 1 冊には、彼が博士号を取得しているというものがありました。
Dissertation written during PhD studentship
博士課程中に書かれた論文
His teacher is a very famous physicist
彼の先生は非常に有名な物理学者です
A question came up during class
授業中に質問が出ました
Said the question is very interesting
その質問はとても興味深いと言いました
do it and see what happens
やってみて何が起こるか見てみましょう
He just did it and made a promise
彼はそれを実行し、約束しただけです
This is the simplest paper I have ever seen
これは私が今まで見た中で最も単純な紙です
Of course he has great consequence
もちろん彼には大きな影響がある
These are the two who discovered high temperature very early in 1987
この 2 人は 1987 年の非常に早い時期に高温を発見しました。
Bennel's Swiss and German Mueller
ベンネルのスイスとドイツのミュラー
Take the promise
約束を受け入れてください
Three more in 2003 with two Russians
2003年にはさらに3件、ロシア人2名が参加
Because the American professor took the promise
アメリカ人の教授が約束を守ってくれたから
it's all about theory
すべては理論の問題です
So there are two related to the theory
したがって、理論に関連するものが 2 つあります
out of twelve
12のうち
Ten are related to experiments
10件は実験関連
wait some people i will mention
待ってください、私が言及する人もいます
not all
すべてではない
First we have to remind
まず思い出してもらいたいのは
Because everyone may go to college for a long time
みんな長く大学に行くかもしれないから
Probably a long time ago or in high school what is a resistor
おそらく昔か高校生の頃に抵抗器とは何か
Let's take a look at what zero resistance means
ゼロ抵抗の意味を見てみましょう
Resistors are actually very simple
抵抗は実際には非常に単純です
take a material
材料を取る
Then you add a direct current like
次に、次のような直流を追加します
add a battery
バッテリーを追加する
Current flows from positive to negative
電流はプラスからマイナスに流れる
That's what we both said
それは私たち二人とも言ったことです
Just put a Ford battery
フォードのバッテリーを入れるだけ
Then how many tenths of an ampere do I have
では、私は何アンペアを持っていますか
I divide it and I am my resistor
私はそれを分割し、私は私の抵抗者です
That resistance is just ohms
その抵抗はちょうどオームです
But this is of course a bit simple
しかし、もちろんこれは少し単純です
because this thing has a problem
これには問題があるから
Let's say that if the length becomes longer
長さが長くなったらとしましょう
If say the length of this conductor is doubled
この導体の長さを2倍にすると、
Then of course we are as small as water
もちろん、私たちは水のように小さいです
if you manage to double
2倍にできたら
your flow is reduced by half
あなたの流量は半分に減少します
Cut the current in half
電流を半分に減らす
then you double the resistance
そうすると抵抗が2倍になります
because you cut this in half
これを半分に切ったから
If the entire value remains unchanged
全体の値が変わらない場合
you just doubled
あなたはちょうど2倍になりました
this resistor
この抵抗器
Then if you take this area
じゃあこのエリアを取ると
double doubled
ダブルダブル
then the current doubles
それから現在のダブルス
we all know that
我々はすべてそれを知っている
If the tube is doubled
チューブが二重になっている場合
the flow of water doubles it
水の流れはそれを2倍にする
Then the resistance is reduced by half
すると抵抗が半分に減ります
So the resistor itself acts as a
したがって、抵抗器自体は次のように機能します。
It depends on the length and area of ​​the material
素材の長さや面積により異なります
It will be different if you measure it
測ってみたら違うだろう
Although both take the same line
どちらも同じ路線をたどりますが、
coarse wire fine wire
粗的導線 細的導線
length you will get different
あなたが得る長さは異なります
so it's not a good number
だからそれは良い数字ではない
because it will experiment with everyone
みんなで実験するから
The amount of this material is different
この材料の量が違います
Although the same
同じですが
but you will measure the difference
でもあなたはその違いを測るでしょう
because this
なぜならこれは
So use a resistivity
したがって、抵抗率を使用します
Using resistivity is not equal to
抵抗率の使用は次と等しくありません
It is only a negative film as a material
素材としてはネガフィルムのみです
so everything
だからすべて
if you check now
今チェックしたら
just check everything
すべてをチェックしてください
arch gold copper silver
アーチ ゴールド 銅 シルバー
have a certain resistivity at room temperature
室温で一定の抵抗率を有する
Then this is a table
それからこれはテーブルです
everyone this is
みんな、これは
If Ohm's Law
オームの法則なら
Then this is electricity
じゃあこれは電気だよ
it's easy
それは簡単です
just like the flow of water
まるで水の流れのように
Water press
ウォータープレス
then you have flow
そうすれば流れができます
And then you just viscosity it
あとは粘度を上げるだけです
This is called a resistor here
ここではこれを抵抗器と呼びます
Then if you are in an ideal body
それで理想の体型になったら
I take this at this time
この時点でこれを受け取ります
A Nature Physics cover that came out to draw the cover
表紙を描くために出たNature Physicsの表紙
draw this beautifully
これを美しく描きます
these atoms
これらの原子
Different sizes represent different atoms
異なるサイズは異なる原子を表します
Ranked seventy-seven
77位
This is our hypothetical ideal body
これが私たちの仮定の理想の体です
Every atom is in its rightful place
すべての原子は適切な場所にあります
A very regular structure arranged neatly
非常に規則的な構造が整然と配置されている
where are you high
どこでハイになっていますか
Plus it's a superconductor
しかも超伝導体だから
It's the same as the blue back
ブルーバックと同じです
This is Wu Maokun Su Jingwu
ウー・マオクン・スー・ジンウーです
this was done
これは行われました
This is the Nano watch award
これがナノウォッチアワードです
No they're the one Bandle Mueller found
いいえ、バンドル・ミュラーが見つけたのは彼らです
This is what you see neatly arranged
こちらも丁寧にアレンジしていただきました
if you imagine this is this
これを想像したらこれです
These atoms are
これらの原子は、
it lined up the whole
全体に並べました
The body is very structured
体は非常に構造的です
Then under such words
それからそのような言葉の下で
of course you can ask
もちろん尋ねることもできます
Where do I get the resistors?
抵抗器はどこで入手できますか?
In fact, there is no resistance
実際、何の抵抗もありません
If your resistor
抵抗器の場合
If it is very powerful
とても強力であれば
It's all the same
それはすべて同じです
You won't have resistors anymore
もう抵抗器は必要ありません
So everyone thought of it before
だから誰もが前にそれを考えました
you may not have a resistor
抵抗器を持っていない可能性があります
the so-called resistance
いわゆる抵抗
The possible reason everyone thinks
誰もが考える考えられる理由
that must be out of alignment
それは故障しているに違いない
One of the reasons is right
理由の一つは正しい
if you these
あなたがこれらの場合
position of some atoms
いくつかの原子の位置
not your usual
いつものことではない
If this position is placed
このポジションに配置されれば
The position of the pendulum
振り子の位置
it went sideways a bit
少し横に逸れてしまいました
a little to the right
少し右に
There is an extra charge in the hole
穴あけには追加料金がかかります
atom
原子
Then when your electrons are running
そしてあなたの電子が走っているとき
will collide
衝突するだろう
Just like everyone sitting here
ここに座っているみんなと同じように
sit well
よく座る
then if you have to go through
通過する必要がある場合
If there is no middle
中間がなければ
Everyone sit well
みんな上手に座ってね
Then if there are a few people crooked
それで、ひねくれた人が数人いたら
Then it will be difficult for you to leave
そうなると離れるのが難しくなるよ
you will hit
あなたは当たるでしょう
Then when you hit this electron
そしてこの電子に当たると
you will have resistance
抵抗があるでしょう
This is where the main resistance comes from
ここが主な抵抗の原因です
It is because of the flash of impurities
不純物のフラッシュのせいです
Of course, a piece as big as the body
もちろん体と同じくらいの大きさの作品
The body is one centimeter in length, width and height
本体は長さ、幅、高さが1センチメートルです
But if it is not perfect, you will have this problem
しかし、それが完璧でない場合、この問題が発生します
This is one of the main sources of resistance.
これは抵抗の主な原因の 1 つです。
This is what everyone probably knew before
これはおそらく誰もが以前から知っていたことです
I'm just talking about the previous resistance problem that reminds everyone
私が話しているのは、誰もが思い出した前回の抵抗の問題についてです。
Every time this resistor hits
この抵抗がヒットするたびに
In fact, it will make this atom move
実際、それはこの原子を動かします
so energy is lost
だからエネルギーが失われる
This is why there is energy when there is resistance
抵抗があるときにエネルギーが存在するのはこのためです
That's what we have in this resistor problem
それがこの抵抗器の問題です
Why is there heat when there is resistance?
抵抗があるとなぜ熱が発生するのでしょうか?
all computers are
すべてのコンピュータは
Most of the heat in all computers is due to the resistance born
すべてのコンピューターの熱のほとんどは抵抗から発生します。
That is, what we are moistening are all resistances.
つまり、私たちが湿らせているのはすべて抵抗です。
So most of the heat comes out of the resistor
したがって、熱のほとんどは抵抗器から出ます。
all electronic everything
すべて電子的なものすべて
this is one of the factors
これは要因の一つです
Of course there is another factor
もちろん別の要因もあります
It's that you arrange these atoms neatly
この原子をきれいに並べることです
They were also disturbed to break up and sat there huddled
彼らもまた別れるのを妨げられ、そこに身を寄せ合って座っていました
It's not like everyone here is doing a good job listening
ここにいる全員がきちんと話を聞いているわけではない
But after a while you probably don't want to move
しかし、しばらくすると、おそらく動きたくないでしょう
Move your hands, move your feet, move your head
手動一下 腳動一下 頭動一下
It also moves on this principle
こちらもこの原則に基づいて動きます
And the reason it moves is of course related to quantum mechanics
そしてそれが動く理由はもちろん量子力学に関連しています
A characteristic of quantum mechanics is that
量子力学の特徴としては、
The more motionless you are, the higher your energy will be
動かないほどエネルギーは高くなります
The more you have to expand your range of motion
可動域を広げなければいけないほど、
In fact, the lower the energy
実は、エネルギーが低ければ低いほど、
This is the Uncertainty Principle of Quantum Mechanics
これが量子力学の不確定性原理です
you may have heard it before
以前に聞いたことがあるかもしれません
this is related to this
これはこれに関連しています
So atoms even at absolute zero temperature
つまり、絶対零度の温度でも原子は
Atoms can still move, it is impossible to stay still
原子はまだ動くことができますが、静止することは不可能です
this thing is troublesome
これは面倒だ
When it moves, you, the electron, are running
それが動くとき、あなたは電子が走っています
will bump into
ぶつかります
Because of it, you were good at first, and everyone took a pat to do it well.
そのおかげで、最初は上手で、みんなも上手にできると太鼓判を押してくれました。
You now hit like this atom passing by
あなたは今、通り過ぎるこの原子のようにぶつかります
atoms hit
原子が当たる
Especially if you're going from one end to the other
特に端から端まで移動する場合
The distance on the other end is
相手側の距離は
Usually we say that less than one is unavoidable
通常、1 未満は避けられないと言われます。
This distance is less than one nanometer
この距離は1ナノメートル未満です
But you have to go from one end of the electron to the other end by walking 10 to the 7th power of Naimi
しかし、電子の一端からもう一端まで、10 のナイミの 7 乗を歩かなければなりません。
It is 7 orders of magnitude of rice
お米の7桁です
That's 10 million times
それは1000万回です
Then of course you have a very high chance of colliding.
そうなると当然、衝突する可能性が非常に高くなります。
bump bump bump bump bump
バンプバンバンバンバンプ
The current becomes very small
電流は非常に小さくなります
Not many pass
合格する人は多くない
That's a lot of heat
すごい熱ですね
So this is also a
したがって、これも
I just said half of what I just said about semiconductors.
私は半導体について今言ったことの半分を言いました。
You see it looks like metal when it's hot
熱いと金属のように見えるのが分かります
Acts like an insulator at low temperatures
低温では絶縁体のように機能します
this is semiconductor
これは半導体です
It's just that it only works for half a day.
ただ、半日しか効果がありません。
then stop
それからやめてください
The metal is completely different.
金属が全然違います。
But the colder it is, the lower its resistance
しかし、寒くなると抵抗力が低下します
This has a feature
これには特徴があります
but when it won't go to zero
でもゼロにならないときは
There is a problem with this
これには問題があります
The performance of this is to say
このパフォーマンスはつまり、
It is a characteristic of metal
金属の特性です
The characteristics of that semiconductor
その半導体の特徴
If it is an insulator, it will run up from the beginning
絶縁体なら最初から駆け上がる
It just looks like there's no resistance and it's very high
抵抗がないように見えますが、非常に高いです
That's another reason
それは別の理由です
the atom itself
原子そのもの
That is, you have grown a very good body
つまり、とても立派な体に成長したのです
That atom is not very safe
その原子はあまり安全ではありません
Then this will also cause resistance
そうするとこれも抵抗が生じる
There is another one, of course
もちろんもう一つあります
The problem with electrons is that they all carry a charge
電子の問題は、電子がすべて電荷を持っていることです。
same charge
同料金
We all know that like charges repel each other.
私たちは皆、同じ電荷が互いに反発することを知っています。
cool wheel force
酷輪作用力
Everyone remembers this
誰もがこれを覚えています
Then of course the cool wheel force can cause problems too.
もちろん、ホイールの冷却力も問題を引き起こす可能性があります。
Then your electron will hit you as soon as you move.
そうすれば、あなたが動くとすぐに電子があなたにぶつかります。
This cool wheel force affects the battery next door
このクールな車輪の力が隣のバッテリーに影響を与える
next to the battery
バッテリーの隣に
all will be affected
すべてが影響を受けるでしょう
if you go astray
道に迷ったら
you should have gone like this
あなたはこうすべきだった
Everyone should go like this
みんなこうやって行けばいいよ
when the current flows
電流が流れるとき
we all want to go together
みんなで一緒に行きたいです
you come across this EY
あなたはこのEYに出会いました
you will hit other
他に当たるでしょう
hit hit hit hit
ヒットヒットヒットヒットヒット
hit a lot of electrons
たくさんの電子をぶつける
Then the whole scattering is very troublesome
それから全体の散乱は非常に厄介です
becomes a very fast loss of energy
エネルギーが非常に早く失われる
Then the current becomes smaller
すると電流は小さくなります
It hit a lot of water pipes
たくさんの水道管にぶつかりました
something other than water flowing past
流れてくる水以外の何か
will hit
当たるだろう
your miscosy gets bigger
あなたの悪趣味が大きくなる
the same principle
同じ原理
So the main thing I'm talking about here is these factors.
したがって、私がここで話している主なことはこれらの要因です。
This problem is what I just said about resistors.
この質問は、私が抵抗について先ほど述べたことと同じです。
just said it was mentioned
言及されただけだと言いました
Is this resistor really 0?
この抵抗は本当に 0 なのでしょうか?
10 negative quad ohms
10 マイナス クワッド オーム
You say you look small when measured
測ると小さく見えるって言うけど
If you change what I just said today
今日言ったことを変えるなら
Change your same material to increase the section area
同じ材質を変更して断面積を増やす
Isn't the resistance half
抵抗が半分じゃないですか
then you're smaller again
そしたらまた小さくなったね
Then if you make this material longer
次に、この素​​材を長くすると
double the resistance
抵抗が2倍になる
right
右
That means you are 0 or not 0
それはあなたが0であるか0ではないということです
If it is 0, how can I width and length
0の場合、幅と長さはどうすればよいですか
it should all be 0
すべて0になるはずです
So are you really 0?
それであなたは本当に0ですか？
Or your equipment is not very good
それとも設備があまり良くないのか
Of course in 1911 I don't think the instruments are very good
もちろん1911年当時の楽器はあまり良くないと思います
we all know
私たちは皆知っています
This is far from now
これは今から遠い
Is the small 0 of water really 0?
水の小さな0は本当に0なのでしょうか？
So why not 0.00001?
では、なぜ 0.00001 ではないのでしょうか?
plus a 0
プラス0
10-6 is 0
10-6は0です
that's not 0
それは0ではありません
So this topic is kind of interesting
ということで、この話題はちょっと面白いですね
is what is called 0
いわゆる0です
Certainly a very special concept
確かに非常に特別なコンセプトです
i remember where i read
どこで読んだか覚えています
0 Chinese people did not have 0 at the beginning
中国人は最初から0ではなかった
It seems that there is no 0 in Chinese numbers.
中国の数字には0がないそうです。
When it hits 0, it jumps over
0になると飛び越える
We have negative certificates but no 0
陰性証明書はありますが、0はありません
But it seems that a mathematician in India invented
しかし、インドの数学者が発明したようです
it's a bold move
それは大胆な行動だ
This proxy is really 0
このプロキシは実際には 0 です
the question of course
もちろんの質問
someone will bring it up soon
誰かがすぐにそれを取り上げるでしょう
you see this you say 0
これを見たあなたは0と言います
So he didn't dare to say 0 o'clock
だから彼はあえて0時とは言わなかった
His name is supercanda
彼の名前はスーパーカンダです
he got a good name
彼は良い名前を持っています
called super
スーパーと呼ばれる
Not small things call it super
小さなことではなくそれをスーパーと呼ぶ
Probably a very good idea
おそらくとても良いアイデアだと思います
this is a good thing
これは良いことだ
so he called super
それで彼はスーパーに電話した
This is English, this word is very useful
これは英語です、この言葉はとても便利です
Of course, there will be a challenge immediately
もちろん、すぐに挑戦します
Better Instruments More Accurate Measurements
より良い機器でより正確な測定を実現
can i get this
これをもらえますか
How to do it?
どうやってするの？
then they say
それから彼らは言います
if we just said
もし私たちがただ言ったら
voltage equals current times resistance
電圧は電流と抵抗の積に等しい
right? everyone has learned this
そうでしょう？誰もがこれを学びました
If you say this thing is equal to 0
これが 0 に等しいと言ったら
If there is a thing
何かあれば
The right side here is equal to 0
ここの右辺は 0 に等しい
Of course, the left side must be equal to 0
もちろん、左辺は 0 に等しくなければなりません
That means I didn't add the battery
つまりバッテリーを追加しなかったということです
I can also have current
現在も持つことができます
How is that?
それはどうですか？
Let's say you start by adding a little bit of voltage
電圧を少し加えて始めるとしましょう
Let the current start to run and then exceed
電流が流れ始めてそれを超えるようにします
Then you take the battery away
それからバッテリーを外します
most of the material
材料のほとんどが
If you do this the battery will die immediately
そんなことをするとすぐにバッテリーが上がってしまいます
you can measure
測定できます
Everyone knows that there will be no current
流れがなくなることは誰もが知っています
If you take the usual conductor
いつもの車掌に乗れば
you do this
これをして
the current will be back soon
流れはすぐに戻るだろう
Then they did this experiment
それから彼らはこの実験を行いました
take it away
それを奪ってください
just let the current run
ただ電流を流してください
As soon as it runs it takes the battery away
走らせるとすぐにバッテリーが消耗してしまう
then watch
それから見てください
When will this current disappear
この流れはいつ消えるのか
This is a good TES
これは良いTESです
If you have resistance
抵抗がある場合
it's gone
なくなってしまった
Then they went for more than a year
それから彼らは1年以上続けました
This is really an experiment
これはまさに実験です
more than a year
1年以上
This current is almost
この流れはほぼ
Of course they can't wait any longer
もちろん、彼らはこれ以上待つことはできません
It is also difficult to write paper
紙を書くのも難しい
Even a little bit is fine
少しでもいいです
almost you are small
ほとんどあなたは小さいです
It means there is little resistance
抵抗が少ないということですね
The current estimate is 10-2
現在の予想は10対2です
Is its square ohm meter
平方オームメーターです
is resistivity
抵抗率です
Of course this is the best instrument
もちろんこれが最高の楽器です
may be this orum
これがオルムかもしれない
In fact the result
実際に結果は
then very important
それからとても重要な
it is not 0.0001
0.0001ではありません
It is likely to be exactly 0
ちょうど 0 になる可能性が高い
this is interesting
これは面白い
because most things
なぜなら、ほとんどのことは
We learn things like
私たちは次のようなことを学びます
you have many decimal points
小数点がたくさんあります
you can take 10-6
10-6 を取ることができます
What - 100 times
何 - 100回
Just -100 is not 0
-100だけでは0ではありません
How do you say it is exactly 0
正確に0だとどう言いますか
this is an interesting question
これは興味深い質問です
we have words for each of you
皆さん一人ひとりに言葉があります
It's easy to say 0
0と言うのは簡単です
If we are 1 2 3
私たちが 1 2 3 なら
we say one person two people
1人2人と言います
You can say that the 0 people are no one in the room
0 人は部屋に誰もいないと言えるでしょう
Of course then I thought there was a problem
もちろん、そのときは問題があると思いました
Someone comes in with one foot, do you want to count it as 0.3 people
片足で入ってくる人がいるけど、0.3人として数えますか？
it's a bit of a hassle
それは少し面倒です
But if you use him to count, you will say 1, 2, 3
でも、彼を使って数えるなら、1、2、3と言うでしょう
-1-2, 0 is very simple
-1-2、0は非常にシンプルです
But what if you want to count by 10, 0.001, 0.001, 0.001?
しかし、10、0.001、0.001、0.001 ずつ数えたい場合はどうすればよいでしょうか?
This reminds me of the Sanju Qing'an in Taiwan a while ago
少し前の台湾の三州青安を思い出します。
If you want to subtract 0, it will be troublesome. What is 0 minus?
0を引きたい場合は面倒ですが、0マイナスとは何でしょうか？
This obviously depends a lot on what instrument you're using.
これは明らかに、使用している楽器に大きく依存します。
It's just that the equipment I just mentioned is a bit rotten.
ただ、先ほどの装備がちょっと腐ってます。
You subtract everything from 0, because you can't measure anything
何も測定できないので、0からすべてを引きます。
But if you use a good instrument, nothing is 0 minus
でも良い楽器を使えば0マイナスなんてことはない
because there is something to see
見るべきものがあるから
So this thing is here, and this is the same
つまり、これはここにあり、これは同じです
This question is of course a long time quarrel, isn't it exactly 0?
この質問はもちろん長年の喧嘩で、まさに0ではないでしょうか？
But what I'm talking about here is that this is the real 0
しかし、私がここで話しているのは、これが本当の 0 であるということです。
exactly 0, mathematically you can say it is precisely
ちょうど 0、数学的には正確に 0 であると言えます
not that almost
ほとんどそうではありません
or not there is or there is not
あるのか、ないのか
It only has one or no resistance or no resistance
抵抗が 1 つしかない、または抵抗がない
The one without resistance is exactly no resistance
抵抗のないものはまさに抵抗がない
So this state is immediately small from this perspective.
したがって、この観点から見ると、この状態はすぐに小さいです。
Because in physics we study classical physics
なぜなら物理学では古典物理学を研究するからです
What variables and phenomena are continuous
どのような変数や現象が連続的であるか
0.001 is fine, you look at 0.001
0.001 でいいです、0.001 を見てください。
Keep going, you measure more and more
続けて、どんどん測定してください
decimal point but never exactly
小数点はありますが、決して正確ではありません
but in quantum mechanics
しかし量子力学では
everything is discrete
すべてが離散的である
So when you see this you know
だから、これを見たらわかるよ
This state is beyond our classical understanding
この状態は私たちの古典的な理解を超えています
state, the electron enters a new state
状態、電子は新しい状態に入ります
The electron suddenly changed
電子が突然変化した
It becomes a product of a quantum
それは量子の産物になる
it must be bright small
小さくて明るいはずだ
Otherwise it wouldn't be exacting
そうでなければ厳密なものではないでしょう
only bright
明るいだけ
we are 1 2 3 0
私たちは 1 2 3 0
Now of course there are other examples
もちろん他の例もあります
some other its conductance
他のコンダクタンス
are called bright numbers
明るい数字と呼ばれます
This is all because of the small size of the light
これはすべてライトのサイズが小さいためです
It is not an ordinary material
普通の素材ではありません
you can see it
見れば分かります
this is the first point
これが最初のポイントです
it is bright small
小さくて明るいです
At first this guide
まずはこのガイド
did not understand this
これは理解できませんでした
so didn't give that onus
だからそんな義務は与えなかった
Because of discovery manipulation
発見操作のせいで
This discovery is of course an extraordinary thing
この発見はもちろん驚くべきものです
for finding a new quantum
新しい量子を見つけるために
of course at that time
もちろんその時は
We've only just begun with the mechanics of the light
光の仕組みはまだ始まったばかりです
don't understand at all
完全不理解
I don't even dare to say now
今さら言う勇気もありません
Our understanding of the mechanics of light
光の仕組みについての私たちの理解
just we know how to use it
ただ私たちは使い方を知っているだけです
wait a minute we'll talk
ちょっと待ってください、話しますから
But it can have a definite
しかし、それは決定的なものを持つことができます
We know that it must be discrete
離散的である必要があることはわかっています
discontinuity
不連続
This is a characteristic of the leon phenomenon
これはレオン現象の特徴です
give it many other features
他にも多くの機能を追加する
Like the uncertainty principle just mentioned, etc.
先ほどの不確定性原理など。
well-known phenomenon
よく知られた現象
that this is a feature
これが特徴だということ
is discrete
離散的です
it is not a continuum
それは連続体ではありません
Then everyone knows this very clearly, right?
そうすると、誰もがこれをはっきりと知っていますよね？
If you look at the periodic table
周期表を見てみると
Did you learn the periodic table
周期表を学びましたか
It is very hard to memorize this periodic table
この周期表を覚えるのはとても難しいです
i can never get it back
決して取り戻すことはできません
But if the periodic table is here
でももし周期表がここにあるなら
You look carefully at every periodic table
すべての周期表を注意深く見てください
How does it define its atomic number
原子番号はどのように定義されますか
It is like this is this Sodium
これがナトリウムみたいな
Then its electron is an orbital
するとその電子は軌道になります
It's called ES2,2S2P6
それはES2,2S2P6と呼ばれます
Then you see it is represented by numbers
すると、それが数字で表されていることが分かります
very discreet
非常discreet的
Discrete
離散
it is not a continuous
それは連続的ではありません
Nothing 0.99sqa
なし 0.99sqa
it has a special track for everything
すべてに特別なトラックがあります
its orbit is discrete
その軌道は離散的です
Then all these things are according to this card
そうすれば、これらすべてはこのカードに従っています
Of course, the real inside is a little richer than this.
もちろん、実際の内部はこれよりもう少し豊かです。
But it is a discrete
しかし、それは離散的です
It's very simple, it's an electron
とてもシンプルです、電子です
the one we just talked about
私たちが今話したもの
The electrons in the conductor are 10 in the 23-foot room
導体の電子は 23 フィートの部屋では 10 個です
There are 10 to 23 electrons in a conductor of one centimeter or three centimeters
1センチメートルまたは3センチメートルの導体には10から23個の電子があります
But it is also discrete
しかし、それは離散的でもあります
That is of course a very miraculous thing
それはもちろんとても奇跡的なことです
This is just an example, the quantum mechanics that everyone is familiar with must be discrete
これはほんの一例ですが、誰もがよく知っている量子力学は離散でなければなりません
This theory was solved in 1957
この理論は 1957 年に解決されました
They held it in 1973 and don't talk about it
彼らは1973年にそれを開催しましたが、それについては話していません
It is very surprising that this theory was proposed in 1957
この理論が 1957 年に提案されたことは非常に驚くべきことです
because they solved the problem
彼らは問題を解決したので
Of course, many people do not get this question completely right.
もちろん、多くの人がこの質問を完全に正しく理解しているわけではありません。
they are totally right
彼らは完全に正しいです
They not only explain the mechanism of superconductivity
超伝導のメカニズムを説明するだけではありません
Also explains the quantum state of superconductivity
超伝導の量子状態も解説
The whole topic starts from using quantum physics to solve this problem
このトピック全体は、量子物理学を使用してこの問題を解決することから始まります。
that can fully explain
それは完全に説明できる
Of course it's amazing
もちろんすごいですよ
amazing job
素晴らしい仕事
able to explain the problem
問題を一度説明できる
Of course there are a lot of new ideas coming from here
もちろん、ここから新しいアイデアがたくさん生まれます
They don't even know they've done it themselves.
彼らは自分たちがそれをやったことさえ知りません。
Some are amazing new ideas
驚くべき新しいアイデアもあります
This was of course understood later
これは当然後になって理解されました
Let me explain their main theories a little bit today
今日は彼らの主な理論を少し説明しましょう
Why does this mechanism exceed
なぜこの仕組みが超過するのか
Electronics, we know that besides electric nuclear, there are optional
エレクトロニクスでは、電気核以外にもオプションの電子機器があることを私たちは知っています。
Everyone says that electrons revolve around themselves
電子は自分の周りを回っていると誰もが言う
In fact, of course, with a unique concept
実は、もちろんユニークなコンセプトで
Actually it has one thing
実はそれには一つのことがあります
like optional
オプションのような
it can have up or down
上下がある可能性があります
By or by or whatever you say
あるいはあなたが言うことによって
Anyway, there are two states
とにかく状態が２つある
it sometimes goes up and sometimes it goes down
上がることもあれば下がることもあります
This thing is powerful
こいつは強力だ
So it can work in strength
それで力強く働くことができる
Therefore, in addition to the energy expansion effect between electrons and electrons
したがって、電子と電子間のエネルギー膨張効果に加えて、
In addition to this, it also has the effect of strength
これに加えて、強度を高める効果もあります
There are also continuous words with atoms and ions
原子やイオンが連続する単語もあります
it will all work
それはすべてうまくいきます
Well here are some new
さて、ここにいくつかの新しいものがあります
The characteristic of this theory is that
この理論の特徴は、
They have a guy named Cooper
彼らにはクーパーという男がいる
Then CooperPay is pairing
次に、CooperPay がペアリングされます
Electronic pairing is called CooperPay
電子ペアリングは CooperPay と呼ばれます
is its most important job
最も重要な仕事です
It states that electrons can form a pair
電子は対を形成できると述べています
Especially these two electrons
特にこの2つの電子
Different choices can form a pair
異なる選択肢がペアを形成する可能性がある
This is a simple Picture that says
これは簡単な写真です。
they will form a pair
彼らはペアを形成します
then of course you are weird
それならもちろんあなたは変です
There is Kuren force in it
そこにはクレンフォースがいる
how does it come to form a pair
どのようにしてペアが形成されるのでしょうか
what makes it pair
何がペアになるのか
because it clearly should exclude
明らかに除外する必要があるため
then how does it pair
ではどうやってペアリングするのか
what about this pairing
この組み合わせはどうですか
that question of course
もちろんその質問は
They came up with a mechanism
彼らはあるメカニズムを思いついた
of course proven
もちろん証明済み
Otherwise, I wouldn't be speaking outside
そうでなければ外で話すことはないでしょう
Experiments Many experiments have shown
実験 多くの実験が示しています
The mechanism is actually quite simple
実はその仕組みはとてもシンプルで、
From that point of view
その観点からすると
because we know
私たちは知っているから
In addition to the electrons in the meridian
子午線内の電子に加えて
You still have ions, right?
イオンはまだありますよね？
shock drive
ショックドライブ
because its electrons run away
電子が逃げるから
run around
走り回る
have one or two electrons
1つまたは2つの電子を持っています
don't follow this atom box
このアトムボックスをフォローしないでください
it ran out by itself and wandered around
勝手に飛び出して歩き回った
Its atomic box is of course the shock driver
その原子箱はもちろんショックドライバーです
electron is attached
電子が付いている
you atomic box
あなたはアトミックボックス
will again
またします
This ion will vibrate
このイオンは振動します
this is what we just said
これが私たちが今言ったことです
oscillate to oscillate
振動する
So if you say you have a
持っていると言うなら、
Electrons go here first
電子は最初にここに行きます
Atom boxes next to these two
これら 2 つの隣の Atom ボックス
Because it's shocking
衝撃的だから
see additional
追加参照
Of course they squeeze in
もちろん彼らは押し込みます
like
好き
if we have this here
ここにこれがあれば
different gender
異なる性別
It's all about a woman
それはすべて女性に関するものです
sit here
ここに座ってください
come closer
もっと近くに来て
the role of this
これの役割
created a little attraction
ちょっとした魅力を生み出しました
this attraction
このアトラクション
Then when the two atomic boxes are close together
次に、2 つの原子ボックスが近づくと、
just a little bit more shocking
もう少しだけ衝撃的だった
because it appends
追加するので
If those two are aligned
この二つが揃っていれば
These two add up to one more regular price
これら 2 つを合計すると通常料金が 1 つ増えます
The other electron also wants to join in the fun
もう一方の電子も楽しみに参加したいと考えています
between such mutual influences
そんな相互影響の間で
on this principle
この原則に基づいて
From another point of view, it is equal to these atomic boxes
別の観点から見ると、これらのアトミックボックスに相当します
dug a hole
穴を掘った
Those two electrons jumped in
その2つの電子が飛び込んできた
It's because of this atomic hole
それはこの原子ホールのせいです
So you electronic background
それで、あなたは電子背景を持っています
it ran in one by two
それは一人ずつ走っていきました
Just take this potential
この可能性を受け入れてください
This negative failed to increase
このマイナスは増加しませんでした
Negative fails to add another electron
マイナスは電子を追加できません
just saw again
また見たばかりです
have jumped in
飛び込んできた
So these two are starting to become each other
だからこの二人はお互いになり始めている
attracting
引き寄せる
This is of course a very simple diagram.
もちろん、これは非常に単純な図です。
This situation means that the child
この状況は、子供が
We call this child
私たちはこの子をこう呼びます
ion vibration
イオン振動
we call birth
私たちは誕生と呼びます
on sound transmission
音の伝達について
your metal
あなたの金属
If you hit it, there will be a sound transmission
叩くと音が伝わります
That sound is transmitted by this vibration
音の伝達はこの振動によって決まります
The vibration of this atom
この原子の振動は
Then this vibration is giving birth
そしてこの振動が産み出す
Then this child is acting
じゃあこの子は演技してるのね
Eliminate a Glu combination
グルタミン酸の組み合わせを排除する
just out of medicine
薬が切れたばかりの
it comes here
それはここに来ます
grab these two
この２つを掴んで
the two of them can be exchanged
二人は交換可能です
information can work
情報は機能する可能性がある
If this is strong enough to dig the composition
これが組成を掘るのに十分な強さであれば
It's better if their repulsion isn't that strong.
反発力はそれほど強くない方が良いです。
Of course, this fitting picture is drawn very small
もちろん、このぴったりの絵はとても小さく描かれています
real time
リアルタイム
The distance between these two pads can be quite far
これら 2 つのパッド間の距離は非常に遠い場合があります
If we each count as a round
それぞれをラウンドとして数えると
If it fits
それが合うなら
if you sit here
ここに座ったら
These two cushions can be partitioned behind the wall
この2つのクッションは壁の後ろで間仕切ることができます
this pair of electrons
この電子対
So the mat pairs in question are not necessarily the closest neighbors
したがって、問題のマット ペアは必ずしも最も近い隣接マットであるとは限りません。
it can pad for a long distance
長距離をパッドすることができます
This can also cause this reaction
これもこの反応を引き起こす可能性があります
Dara has a few special ones in it
ダラには特別なものがいくつかあります
What it says is that the vibration of the rope is very important
ロープの振動が非常に重要だということです。
it will produce
それは生成します
if it doesn't work with the rope
ロープでうまくいかない場合
I said if these things can't move
これらが動かないならと私は言った
fix it there then it's gone
そこで修正してください、その後は消えます
that doesn't need a guide
それはガイドを必要としません
Because we can have perfect love
完璧な愛ができるから
The ideal classic also has no resistance
理想のクラシックにも抵抗がない
But that one has no resistance
でもあの人は抵抗がない
It's a completely different mechanism than this
これとは全く違う仕組みです
this is there
これはそこにあります
But it creates another situation
しかし、それは別の状況を生み出します
no resistance
抵抗がない
It goes from having a resistor to one without a resistor
抵抗ありから抵抗なしへ
The most important thing is that it will form a CouplePet
最も重要なことは、CouplePet を形成することです。
That's what CouplePet has
それがCouplePetの特徴です
So why is there no resistance?
では、なぜ抵抗がないのでしょうか？
This is what I found for a painting
これは私が見つけた絵画です
the russian painter
ロシアの画家
Drawings by Pervoninsky
ペルボニンスキーの素描
I think this is my favorite way to express
これが私の一番好きな表現方法だと思います
The end electrons in the CouplePet pair
couplePet ペアの末端電子
what to do in there
そこで何をするか
Like so many people dancing Wars
たくさんの人がウォーズを踊っているように
waltz
ワルツ
in that hall
あのホールで
you see so many people jumping
たくさんの人がジャンプしているのが見えます
A man and a woman are making noise
男と女が騒いでいる
Then you can exchange pottener with each other
そうすれば陶芸家同士を交換することができます
Exchange your Pay
給料を交換する
can be exchanged
交換できます
How does he turn?
それでは彼はどうやって向きを変えるのでしょうか？
here again
またここで
There are flowers, chairs, tables, and pillars
花、椅子、テーブル、柱があります
no problem
問題ない
it keeps turning around
それは回り続ける
The whole weave jumps
織り全体がジャンプします
so you can imagine
想像できるように
Suppose there is such a beautiful
こんな美しいものがあったとしよう
so many teams jumping over there
非常に多くのチームがそこにジャンプしています
how to dance
踊り方
dancing to the music
音楽に合わせて踊る
don't imagine each other
お互いを想像しないでください
won't run into any obstacles
障害物にぶつからない
What kind of pillars are the tables and chairs?
テーブルや椅子の柱は何ですか？
just can go around
ただ回ることができる
no matter what
何があっても
and then exchange each other
そしてお互いに交換します
of these two
この二つのうち
can't express it all
すべてを表現することはできません
Because the two of them are still close
二人は今でも仲が良いので
but you can imagine
でも想像できるだろう
some dancing
いくつかのダンス
We could have separated when we were kids
私たちが子供の頃に別れたかもしれない
two jump like this
あと2人はこのようにジャンプします
then go over
それから行きます
jump like this
こうやってジャンプする
then if you imagine
それから想像してみたら
In the current situation
現状では
That's what all the electrons are doing
それがすべての電子がやっていることです
The electrons are divided one by one
電子が一つずつ分かれる
Well done
素晴らしい
That is the last election
それが最後の選挙です
Next time choose one to one red electron
次回は1対1の赤電子を選択します
Every electron can see
すべての電子は見ることができます
it's one come one red
それはワンカムワンレッドです
just jump each other once
一度だけお互いにジャンプしてください
This is probably the most beautiful dancing episode
これはおそらく最も美しいダンスのエピソードです
no matter how you dance
どんなに踊っても
They are all very synchronized
みんなすごくシンクロしてるよ
then this is real
それならこれは本物だ
it's a huge amount
それは膨大な量です
Why talk about macro
なぜマクロについて話すのか
Because it's not about an electron
電子の話じゃないから
two electrons
2つの電子
real
本物
This 23rd power electron
この23乗の電子は
Tongtong is doing the same thing
トントンも同じことやってる
this is incredible
これが信じられない
This miracle of nature is
この自然の奇跡は、
far more than we think
私たちが思っているよりもはるかに
how do you get all the electrons
どうやってすべての電子を手に入れるのですか
They all do this synchronous operation
それらはすべてこの同期操作を実行します
and won't install that episode
そのエピソードはインストールされません
so no electrons
だから電子がない
there are these pillars
これらの柱があります
What table and chairs are there in the middle?
真ん中にあるテーブルと椅子は何ですか?
also won't pretend
ふりもしない
It's all over
すべて終わった
These can also jump farther
これらはさらに遠くまでジャンプすることもできます
that's what i'm talking about here
それが私がここで話していることです
one there
そこに一つ
how much are you right
あなたはどれくらい正しいですか
dance here
ここで踊ってください
So there are many pairs in between
したがって、間には多くのペアが存在します
But I can still pair with that
しかし、私はまだそれとペアリングすることができます
you paired with that
あなたはそれとペアになりました
jumping
ジャンピング
But this is the closest I found
しかし、これが私が見つけた中で最も近いものです
I can't find a better icon
これより良いアイコンが見つかりませんでした
if you go and close your eyes
行って目を閉じたら
think about this scenario
このシナリオについて考えてください
Just thought this is so beautiful
これはとても美しいと思った
This real physics is indeed very beautiful
この現実の物理学は実に美しい
It's so hard to imagine
想像するのはとても難しいです
then they are not human
それなら彼らは人間ではない
How can they be so harmonious
どうして彼らはそんなに調和できるのでしょうか
such
そのような
this is what i said
これは私が言ったことです
This coordination and harmony synchronize
この調和と調和がシンクロする
this word is hard to come by
この言葉は難しいです
but they do it all
しかし、彼らはすべてをやっています
So that means that every electron
つまり、すべての電子は
is actually doing the same thing for every electron
実際にはすべての電子に対して同じことを行っています
Of course, we cannot tell the difference between electrons and electrons.
もちろん、電子と電子の違いはわかりません。
people we can see
私たちに見える人々
This man has a beard and no beard
この男性にはひげがありますが、ひげはありません
that just means
それはただの意味です
Of course you can't tell the difference
もちろん違いはわかりません
This is the electronics rack
こちらは電子機器ラックです
electronic handle
電子柄
of course not
もちろん違います
Then all the electrons are like
すると、すべての電子は次のようになる
Then of course all electrons do the same thing
もちろん、すべての電子は同じことをします
This is the real view. It's too good.
これが本当の景色だ、もったいない。
Then this can also be exchanged partners
そうすれば、これもパートナーを交換できます
Of course I won't say more now
もちろん今はそれ以上は言いません
It also goes in the opposite direction
逆方向にも行きます
I just didn't say
ただ言わなかった
I can't fix this picture
この写真は修正できません
you go ahead
どうぞ
This is your cooperation
これはあなたの協力です
go here mate, go here
ここに行きなさい、相棒、ここに行きなさい
if you go to the right, it goes to the left
右に行けば左に行く
If you go backwards, it will go backwards
逆行すれば逆行するよ
walk in the opposite direction, all steps
すべてのステップで反対方向に歩きます
So it's like dancing
だからダンスみたいだ
Because this pace is to match
このペースが合うから
The console of the same nature doesn't like it
同じ性質のコンソールはそれを好みません
Of course, because of this same article, it doesn't like it
もちろん、同じ記事なので気に入らない
You will be paired to guess good, subject to different
あなたはペアになって、さまざまな状況に応じて良い推測をすることになります
Because as you can imagine, it dances so harmoniously
やっぱり、とても和気あいあいと踊るから
If someone suddenly sees
誰かが突然見たら
That's terrible, many people next to me will follow suit
それはひどい、私の隣にいる多くの人が追随するでしょう
a lot is going to go wrong
多くのことがうまくいかないだろう
If someone goes to a dance buddy one hits the wall
誰かがダンス仲間のところに行くと、壁にぶつかります
The other one will be miserable
もう一人は悲惨になるだろう
Someone next to me will hit the wall
隣の人が壁にぶつかるだろう
Creates a lot of matching at once , guess good
一度に多くのマッチングを作成します。良いと思います
This is not a good thing, it will be lost
これは良くないことだ、失われてしまうだろう
Just now I saw that one of them dug a trap
たった今、彼らのうちの一人が罠を掘っているのを見ました
Now if you want to guess Shan, there will be no more
シャンを推測したければ、これ以上はありません
there is no way
道はない
The other one is, if you say
もう一つは、言ってみれば、
The pair of blue and red in the middle is jumping
真ん中の青と赤のペアがジャンプしています
The blue ones are much more than the red ones, so how do you match them?
青いものは赤いものよりもはるかに多いので、どうやってそれらを一致させるのでしょうか？
one question
一つの質問
Difficult to match even if the numbers are different
数字が違っても一致するのは難しい
how to become a guide
ガイドになる方法
So both of these will cause manipulation
したがって、これらは両方とも操作を引き起こすことになります
unstable attitude
不安定な姿勢
Then this is of course the CooperPair
それから、これはもちろん CooperPair です
broke it apart
それを壊した
That's because it's too much
それは多すぎるからです
CooperPair has an up and a down
CooperPairには上昇と下降があります
There are a lot more up than down.
下りよりも上りのほうが多いです。
no right
権利はありません
dancing alone
一人で踊る
Of course it is not possible
もちろんそれは不可能です
performance evenly
均等なパフォーマンス
In fact, this thing is an external magnetic field
実はこれは外部磁場なのです
will cause the phenomenon
現象を引き起こします
Because the electron I just mentioned has
なぜなら、今言った電子は
self-taught backspin
独学で学んだバックスピン
it is magnetic
それは磁気です
So the magnetic field will affect it
だから磁場の影響を受けるんだよ
The influence of the magnetic field will cause these things
磁場の影響でこんな事が起こります
then this is what we are now
それからこれが今の私たちです
Let's do some experiments for you
いくつか実験してみましょう
This is the magnetic field you see
これがあなたが見ている磁場です
Why is there a magnetic field
なぜ磁場があるのか
In fact, it has a lot to do with this
実はこれと大きく関係があるのです
Because this is why it prefers Chen Taitai
これがチェン・タイタイを好む理由だからです
If a magnetic field is forced to be applied, what kind of phenomenon will it produce?
磁場を強制的に加えるとどのような現象が起こるのでしょうか？
Just because it doesn't like this, so it does weird things
これが気に入らないからといって、奇妙なことをするのです
shall we do this demonstration
このデモンストレーションをしましょうか
Of course this will burn, 77 degrees is very cold
もちろんこれは燃えます、77度はとても寒いです
If you take a small piece of metal, it'll all sit in there, and it'll become brittle
小さな金属片を手に入れると、すべてがそこに留まり、脆くなってしまいます
So this is pretty awesome
これはかなりすごいです
so be sure to wear gloves
必ず手袋を着用してください
The experiment it does is to put a magnet on this high-temperature conductor
この高温導体に磁石を付ける実験です。
Hang it up, hang it up from that cup, hang it up
掛けて、そのカップから掛けて、掛けて
Hanging fish is a fun place, there is no line for hanging fish
吊るされた魚は楽しい場所です、吊るされた魚には行列がありません
That is, Jiang Taigong does not use a line to hang fish, and he also does not use a line to hang fish
つまり、蒋太公は魚を吊るすのに糸を使わず、魚を吊るすのにも糸を使いません。
it has no wires but it won't soak
ワイヤーはありませんが、浸み込みません
It can be sent to the high temperature conductor itself
高温導体自体に送ることができる
there is no rope to pull it up
それを引き上げるためのロープはありません
it can pull the material out of it
そこから材料を引き出すことができます
from inside this cup of it
このコップの中から
can go pull it out
引き出しに行ってもいいよ
so it has a magnet on it
なので磁石が付いています
so it's now stuck to its
それで今はそれに固執しています
not your family
あなたの家族ではありません
stick to this
これに固執する
take it take it
取ってください
then if you look carefully
それから注意深く見てみると
it should only be five to ten seconds
わずか 5 ～ 10 秒です
yes you only have five to ten seconds
はい、5 ～ 10 秒しかありません
The reason for my show here is that the light consumption can be rushed through.
ここで私がショーを行う理由は、光の消費を急いで実行できるためです。
there is nothing in it
そこには何もありません
it's grungy
汚いです
Empty, it's just not long enough
空っぽ、長さが足りない
It's about to pull, it's not enough, it's space
引っ張られそう、足りない、スペースだ
But you can see that it's not very stable when you pull it up.
しかし、引き上げてみると、あまり安定していないことがわかります。
wait a minute i'll talk about it this
ちょっと待ってください、これについて話します
Why is it not too stable
なぜ安定しすぎないのか
because when it is held
なぜなら開催されるときは
It was put on after the tide island has been changed.
潮島を変更してから装着しました。
You can see that the two are actually separated
実際に二人が離れていることがわかります
it didn't touch
触れなかった
This itself if not frozen
冷凍していなければこれ自体
it can't be picked up
それは拾うことができません
So this can levitate it
これで空中に浮かせることができます
This is another kind, the magnetic point is below
これは別の種類で、磁力点は下にあります
you can tell it's floating
浮いているのがわかります
and quite stable
そしてかなり安定しています
The one just now was not so stable
さっきのはあまり安定してなかった
this is very stable
これは非常に安定しています
wait there is a reason
待ってください、理由があります
Why is it that one or two are a bit different
1つや2つが少し違うのはなぜですか
It's a magnet that's already on it
すでに付いている磁石です
under this track
このトラックの下で
So it can float
だから浮くことができる
This is floating
これは浮いてるよ
This can last a long time
これは長く続く可能性があります
This time it's completely stopped
今回は完全に止まってます
I keep looking
私は探し続けます
this is so enjoyable
これはとても楽しいです
Of course it's fun to be inside the gate
もちろん門の中にいるのも楽しいです
Not this one
これじゃない
that was done
それは行われました
Somebody make a person this big stand on it and float
誰かこれくらい大きな人をその上に立たせて浮かせてください
this
これ
good
良い
Thanks
ありがとう
thank you both
あなたがた両方に感謝します
good
良い
explained
説明した
The place where this explanation was just now
先ほどこの説明があった場所
it's this thing
それはこれです
The characteristic is the magnetic field of our home
特徴は我が家の磁場
Of course, the magnetic fields of the two homes are actually different.
もちろん、実際には 2 つの家の磁場は異なります。
It can be said that this is
これは言えることだ
Originally, the magnetic field acts on this
本来はこれに磁場が作用するのですが、
Before becoming superconducting
超電導になる前
The magnetic field is already acting on the material
磁場はすでに物質に作用しています
and then you cool it down
そしてそれを冷やします
This one originally had no magnetic field.
これにはもともと磁場がありませんでした。
That you cool it first and then add the magnetic field
まず冷却してから磁場を加えるということ
These two are actually not the same
この 2 つは実際には同じではありません
It can be seen that this is not stable
これは安定していないことがわかります
It's very stable when you pull it up
引き上げるととても安定します
very stable species
非常に安定した種
Of course there is a very simple reason for this
もちろんこれには非常に単純な理由があります
But the most important reason is that these are
しかし、最も重要な理由は、これらが
These superconductors don't like this magnetic field too much
これらの超伝導体はこの磁場をあまり好まない
so what does he do
それで彼は何をしますか
Of course it's easy
もちろん簡単です
drain it
それを排出します
If it's not good and you don't like it, let it out
それが良くなくて気に入らない場合は、外に出してください
is their greatest practice
それは彼らの最大の実践です
Well, of course, the situation of this discharge is like this
さて、今回の放流の様子はもちろんこんな感じです
Usually we think of common metals
通常、私たちはありふれた金属を思い浮かべます。
We all learned about Faraday
みんなファラデーについて学びました
cognitive law
認知法則
That is, if you take a metal
つまり、金属を取ると
with a magnetic field
磁場を使って
when you put in
入れるとき
The magnetic field causes a current in the metal
磁場により金属に電流が発生します
Current is usually
電流は通常、
Sensing direction
検出方向
Just enough to cancel your magnetic field
磁場を打ち消すのにちょうど十分
but ordinary metal
でも普通の金属
not very strong
あまり強くない
because of what
何かのせいで
because of current
現在のせいで
there will be resistance
抵抗があるだろう
at last there will be no more
ついにもうなくなります
The current is gone
電流がなくなった
So other than this is not very strong
なのでこれ以外はあまり強くない
but in dick too
でもディックでも
This current will not disappear
この流れは消えない
So its current can be very strong
したがって、その電流は非常に強い可能性があります
can stay for a long time
長期滞在できる
can generate a strong magnetic field
強力な磁場を発生させることができます
The two magnetic fields are of course opposite to each other.
当然のことながら、2 つの磁場は互いに反対です。
This is called shielding current
これをシールド電流といいます
that you now have
あなたが今持っているもの
the experiment just now
たった今の実験
That is, a magnet is placed under it and above it.
つまり、磁石がその下と上に配置されます。
when it is placed like this
このように置くと
This magnetic field goes from North Pole to South Pole
この磁場は北極から南極まで広がります
When going through this tutorial material
このチュートリアル資料を読み進めるとき
it is squeezed
絞られている
Look at this magnetic force line
この磁力線を見てください
It is logical that it should come down like this
このように下がるのは論理的です
But it's not it's squeezed out
でも絞り出されてるんじゃないよ
How is it squeezed? Because the superconductivity here will generate a current
どうやって絞っているのかというと、ここの超電導によって電流が発生するからです。
Just like ordinary metal, as I just said
先ほども言いましたが、普通の金属と同じです
If you add a permanent, it will generate current
パーマネントを追加すると、電流が生成されます。
The superconducting current will not disappear because it has no resistance
超電導電流は抵抗がないので消えない
So it keeps flowing, and it produces the exact opposite
だからそれは流れ続けて、それは正反対のものを生み出す
It also generates a North Pole here
ここでも北極が生成されます
The two north poles face each other, everyone will move if they know it
二つの北極が向かい合う それを知れば誰もが動く
Yes, take two battery holders
はい、バッテリーホルダーを 2 つ用意してください
Sometimes it's similar, sometimes it's different
似ている場合もあれば、異なる場合もあります
Your North Pole is like the North Pole, and the North Pole is like the South Pole
あなたの北極は北極のようであり、北極は南極のようです
Then it happens to be North Pole to North Pole
そうしたら、たまたま北極から北極へ
This is the famous symbol
これが有名なシンボルです
That is to say, this word has been known for a long time
つまり、この言葉は古くから知られていたのです。
It doesn't have to be superconducting
超電導である必要はない
But with superconductivity, this force becomes much larger
しかし、超電導になると、この力はさらに大きくなります。
This is what I copied from the picture in their Shuangyuehai
これはShuangyuehaiの写真からコピーしたものです
I don't know how to draw this
これの描き方がわかりません
They drew it very well, the magnetic lines look like this
とても上手に描けました、磁力線はこんな感じです
Look at this, bending like this actually creates force
ほら、こうやって曲げると力がかかるんです
Because the lines of force don't like to bend like this
力線はこうやって曲がるのを嫌うから
If you bend it like this, it will only compress tightly.
このように曲げると、しっかりと圧縮されるだけです。
So you can't fall, you can't hold down even with gravity
だから落ちない、重力があっても押さえつけられない
Magnetic lines lift you up
磁力線があなたを引き上げる
At that time, it was also said that there was an arctic market here.
当時、ここには北極市場があったとも言われています。
so lift him up
だから彼を持ち上げてください
that this is amazing
これはすごいことだ
because why doesn't he like
なぜ彼は気に入らないのか
that's what i just said
それが私が今言ったことです
because you're going to ruin his match
あなたは彼の試合を台無しにするつもりだから
You have to make him not able to dance there harmoniously
彼がそこで調和して踊れないようにしなければならない
make him unhappy
彼を不幸にする
what will he do
彼は何をしますか
he puts you out
彼はあなたを追い出す
don't let you eat sugar
砂糖を食べさせないでください
This is of course an interesting thing
これはもちろん興味深いことです
This is what nature does automatically
これは自然が自動的に行うことです
get you out
あなたを出してください
That way, the energy is relatively low.
そうすれば、エネルギーは比較的低くなります。
This is just floating
これはただ浮いているだけです
But this buoy is only repulsive
でもこのブイは反発するだけです
This brain is not very stable
この脳はあまり安定していない
So just now it can be seen
だから今それが見える
then he is not very stable
それから彼はあまり安定していません
In fact, some of this stuff will slowly seep in.
実際、この成分の一部はゆっくりと浸透していきます。
seeps into its edge
端に浸透する
Then this just said that MineSyn
それから、これは MineSyn を言いました
That's what happened just now
それが今起こったことです
In fact, there is another way
実は別の方法もあります
If your magnetic field strength is too high
磁場の強さが高すぎる場合
it has another way
別の方法があります
it can't be discharged
それは排出できません
because you are too strong
あなたは強すぎるから
What should he do then?
彼は何をすべきか？
well , he confines you to a small space
まあ、彼はあなたを小さな空間に閉じ込めます
Think about how clever this nature is
この性質がどれほど賢いか考えてみましょう
Then I can't deal with you, you are too strong
それなら私はあなたに対処できません、あなたは強すぎます
What am I doing? I keep all your magnetic fields small
私は何をしているのですか? 私はあなたの磁場をすべて小さく保ちます
Just like the pillars, the same pillars you just jumped on
柱のように、あなたが飛び乗った同じ柱のように
then i'll be fine i'm old
それなら大丈夫、私は年をとったから
nothing to do with me
私とは何の関係もありません
what he can do
彼に何ができるのか
Someone figured this out
誰かがこれを考え出した
Then this thing is, let's talk about it later and get the road sign to talk about it
それなら、これについては後で話しましょう、そしてそれについて話すために道路標識を手に入れましょう
Well, this thing is very interesting. It's called a mixing station.
これはとても興味深いもので、ミキシング ステーションと呼ばれるものです。
That is, some lines of magnetic force are discharged to the outside, and some are mixed in.
つまり、磁力線の一部は外部に放出され、一部は混入します。
The one in that row, this one is called
その列にあるもの、これはと呼ばれるものです
Just now we called the Myzen effect
今、Myzen 効果と呼んでいました。
It's weird that this guy didn't get the road sign
この男が道路標識を理解できなかったのは奇妙だ
This, this has got the road sign to tell
これ、これに道路標識があります
Arranged in a small space, this is called a mixing table
狭いスペースに配置されたものをミキシングテーブルと呼びます
Well, this is of course very important
まあ、これはもちろん非常に重要です
Then the mixing station mentioned just now is actually even more mysterious if you really look at it carefully.
そして、今言及したミキシングステーションは、実際に注意深く見てみるとさらに神秘的です。
That is, you still had this shielding current just now.
つまり、先ほどもこのシールド電流が流れていました。
I just said that you have shielding current when you hold the field.
フィールドを保持するとシールド電流が流れると先ほど言いました。
This pool line will go in
このプールラインが入ります
Then we discovered the pool line
そしてプールラインを発見
It's actually a pool
実はプールなんです
Each pool line has a certain pool moment
各プールラインには特定のプールモーメントがあります
not casual
カジュアルではない
we usually talk about pool
私たちはいつもプールについて話します
Let's talk about 0.1 high humidity or Tesla
0.1高湿度かテスラについて話しましょう
0.001 is the speed per hour
0.001は時速です
continuous
継続的な
but here to tell you it's not
しかし、ここでそうではないことを伝えたいと思います
In this quantum state
この量子状態では
This thing itself is a quantum number
この物自体が量子数です
Each of these original rights represents a certain basic holding
これらの元の権利はそれぞれ、特定の基本的な所有権を表します。
Everyone is well arranged
みんなきちんと整理整頓されています
Here it's actually neatly drawn
こちらは実際に丁寧に描かれています
Each has six neighboring triangular lattices next to it
各三角格子の隣には 6 つの隣接格子があります
This is Abbey Kossoff narrating
こちらはアビー・コゾフがナレーションをしています
It is what I talked about in 2003 with the Noble Watch
それは私が2003年にNoble Watchについて話した内容です
Just because I solved it
解決したからといって
mainly a job
主に仕事
Let him speak with a watch
彼に時計を見ながら話させてください
Is to lift this Ubricos of lattice
この格子のウブリコスを持ち上げるのが
This proof is of course too much time to prove now
もちろんこの証明は今証明するには時間がかかりすぎる
this is right
これは正しいです
you can go straight to it
すぐにそこに行くことができます
You sprinkle some iron powder on it
鉄粉を振りかけると
You can look directly at this magnetic flux
この磁束を直接見ることができます
how
どうやって
Of course each one has a vortice
もちろんそれぞれに渦がある
there is no superconducting team in it don't like to be in it
そこには超電導チームは存在しない、そこには入りたくない
superconducting team is right outside it
超電導チームはそのすぐ外にあります
All the superconducting teams are out of it
超電導チームは全員駄目だ
make a fuss
大騒ぎをする
It's like you've got lots of assistants and you're dancing
たくさんのアシスタントがいて踊っているようなもの
You are making trouble with the assistant
アシスタントとトラブルを起こしている
then don't run inside
それなら中を走らないでください
That's what they do electronically
それは彼らが電子的にやっていることです
Then this CobraPack is amazing
それからこのCobraPackはすごいです
he would do it himself
彼は自分でやるだろう
and not one or two
そして1つや2つではありません
That's what everyone does
それは誰もがやっていることです
That's what I just said
それが私が今言ったことです
Why is it more stable?
なぜその方が安定しているのでしょうか?
In fact, the magnetic flux is in this
実はこの中に磁束が入っているんです
will also lock
ロックもします
it's somewhere
それはどこかにあります
For example, some impurities
たとえば、いくつかの不純物
it likes to be in the impurities
それは不純物の中にいることを好む
We just said that impurities are not very good, right?
不純物はあまり良くないと言いましたよね？
When there is this magnetism
この磁気があると
This magnetic flux will be hired on the impurity
この磁束が不純物に利用されます。
very strong
とても強い
So just say that
だからそれを言ってください
Just now this experiment here
ちょうど今ここでこの実験が行われています
this small
この小さい
This experiment with this little train
この小さな電車での実験
It's on top of this
この上にあるよ
because it is in the magnetic field
磁場の中にあるから
The magnet is already inside
磁石はすでに入っています
you cool it down
あなたはそれを冷やします
All the magnetic flux goes inside.
磁束はすべて内部に入ります。
just stay in there
ただそこにいてください
so locked
とてもロックされています
equal to lock
ロックに等しい
when you lift it up now
今持ち上げると
This magnetic flux has no place to run
この磁束は逃げ場がない
Everything inside is equivalent to being locked.
内部のものはすべてロックされているのと同じです。
So it's like an invisible rope
それは見えないロープのようなものです
the rope you can't see
見えないロープ
In fact, this material can be smashed
実はこの素材は砕ける可能性があります
very stable
非常に安定した
So it runs very stable
なので非常に安定して動作します
it can't move
それは動けない
because so much
とてもたくさんあるので
stay still
都要定住
it can't move
それは動けない
The one just now is because you didn't add it at the beginning
今のものは最初に追加しなかったためです
no magnet here
ここに磁石はありません
You later surpassed to have
あなたは後にそれを超えました
you want to add
追加したい
In fact it is added next to
実際には次に追加されます
very weak
非常に弱い
beside
それ以外
so it's not very stable
なのであまり安定していません
So I can't live if I smashed it like that just now
だから今あんなに壊したら生きていけないよ
there is a difference between the two
2つの間には違いがあります
If it is placed in a magnetic field first and then cooled
最初に磁場に入れてから冷却した場合
The two results are not the same
2 つの結果は同じではありません
This result is to tell you
この結果が言いたいのは、
This is a company with a very stable employment
雇用がとても安定している会社です
so what can this be used for
それで、これは何に使えますか
can be used as an application
アプリケーションとして使用できます
Now we understand this thing
今、私たちはこのことを理解しています
we also know why
私たちもその理由を知っています
Because the Cooper team wants everyone to be harmonious
クーパーチームは全員が調和することを望んでいるからです
if you mess up
めちゃくちゃになったら
some of the others it's not good
他のいくつかは良くありません
But it has a way to solve this problem
しかし、この問題を解決する方法があります
it can solve this problem
この問題を解決できます
Make a Perfect Solution
完璧なソリューションを作る
All of this I just talked about is consciousness
私が今話したことはすべて意識のことです
Of course quantum mechanics can help you figure it out
もちろん、量子力学はそれを理解するのに役立ちます
Everything I said can be calculated exactly
私が言ったことはすべて正確に計算できます
This is an incredible result of the BCS theory
これは BCS 理論の驚くべき結果です
It is not possible to do this quantitatively
これを定量的に行うことは不可能です
alright
大丈夫
But there is another not-so-good place in BCS theory
しかし、BCS 理論にはもう 1 つ良くない点があります。
Its temperature probably won't exceed 40 degrees
40度を超えることはないだろう
Because someone has done the math on how hard it is for me to increase the temperature
体温を上げるのがどれだけ難しいかを誰かが計算してくれたから
Because it must have a strong electron ion
強い電子イオンを持っているはずなので
We just talked about the role of biomass, right?
先ほどバイオマスの役割についてお話しましたね。
Electrons and biomass must have an attractive force to dig a hole for it to enter
電子とバイオマスには、穴を掘って侵入する引力が必要です
It must be very strong, the stronger it is, the deeper the hole will be dug, and the faster it will fall, right, the better
きっと強いんだろう、強ければ強いほど穴は深くなるし、落ちるのも早くなるだろうね
But you also need a high electron density, that is, a lot of electrons
しかし、高い電子密度、つまり大量の電子も必要です。
At a certain energy, there must be many electrons in a place close to the low energy
あるエネルギーでは、低エネルギーに近い場所に電子がたくさんあるはずです。
But there is no superconductivity without electrons
しかし、電子がなければ超伝導は存在しない
So it's impossible for an insulator to superconduct, right?
つまり、絶縁体が超伝導になることは不可能ですよね？
But if you want to put electrons in it, it needs to be superconducting, the more the better
しかし、電子を入れたい場合は、超伝導である必要があり、多ければ多いほど良いです。
Then these two must be very large, but when these two are very large, there are actually other problems
その場合、これら 2 つは非常に大きいはずですが、これら 2 つが非常に大きい場合、実際には別の問題が発生します。
When this is too strong, like this strong, if this thing is getting stronger
これが強すぎるとき、これが強いとき、これが強くなったら
This electron can't escape anymore
この電子はもう逃げることはできない
Then we just said that it will continue to dance.
それから、踊り続けるだろうと先ほど言いました。
This is not jumping all the time, jumping from here to that two people have to switch
これはずっとジャンプしているわけではなく、ここからジャンプして2人が切り替わる必要があります
run around, then you may...
走り回って、そうすれば...
Synchronize Harmony
シンクロハーモニー
it jumps now if you don't give it
あなたがそれを与えなければ、それは今ジャンプします
Each is fixed in a certain area
それぞれが特定の領域に固定されています
That's an insulator
それは絶縁体です
You cushion it, even if you add cushions, it can’t jump out
クッションを置くと、クッションを追加しても飛び出しません
it can't conduct
それは実行できません
that's over, that's over
それは終わった、それは終わった
So it has a limitation
だから限界があるんだよ
That is to say, if you are too strong
つまり、強すぎると
I can't help it either
それも仕方ないよ
Too weak and I don't have superconductivity
弱すぎて超電導力がない
Then I have to be stronger to resist my rejection point
それから私は自分の拒絶点に抵抗するためにもっと強くならなければなりません
I just said that there is a cool person effect
クールパーソン効果があると言いました
So there is a lot of balance in it
なので、かなりバランスが取れています
have a balance
バランスがある
that sometimes more
それは時々もっと
That's why we want the temperature to be higher, higher and higher
だから温度をもっと高く、高く、高くしたいのです。
Then how do you get this out
じゃあどうやってこれを取り出すのか
So this question was originally
したがって、この質問はもともと
Someone suggested that it is impossible to exceed 40 degrees
誰かが40度を超えることは不可能だと言いました
This question is of course very frustrating
この質問はもちろん非常にイライラさせられます
Because we just showed 1980
1980 年を見せたばかりだから
Of course people who do experiments, people who do physics
もちろん実験をする人、物理をする人
never respond
決して応答しない
What is the limit
限界は何ですか
we still have to try
私たちはまだ努力しなければなりません
keep trying
挑戦し続ける
Then someone tried it
そしたら誰かが試してみた
Then of course do this test
それからもちろんこのテストを実行してください
That's what you see all the way here until 1986
1986年までここまでずっと見えていますね
A total of 74 years later
通算74年後
These two people won the Nobel Prize
この二人がノーベル賞を受賞した
This was in 1913 and he made it in 1911
これは 1913 年のことであり、彼は 1911 年にそれを作りました
He was made in 1986
彼は1986年に作られました
Received the Nobel Prize in 1987
1987年にノーベル賞を受賞
The Battle of Mirror
ミラーの戦い
because why
なぜならなぜ
Because Wu Maokun and Zhu Jinwu helped them dance
ウー・マオクンとジュー・ジンウーがダンスを手伝ってくれたから
jump from here to here
ここからここへジャンプ
this is liquid egg
これは液卵です
So I can now do this experiment and show you guys here
それで、私は今この実験を行って、ここで皆さんにお見せすることができます
because they made the material
彼らが素材を作ったから
it would be hard if i was here
私がここにいたら大変だろう
I'm going to do liquid harm
液体害を与えるつもりだ
Liquid Hazard is very expensive now
リキッドハザードは現在非常に高価です
One liter costs five or six hundred Taiwan dollars
1リットルで500～600台湾ドル
and very troublesome
そしてとても面倒です
evaporated in one go
一気に蒸発した
very expensive
非常に高価な
But liquid eggs are cheap
でも液卵は安いよ
about as cheap as beer
ビールと同じくらい安い
So it's very convenient to follow this
したがって、これに従うと非常に便利です
then i can show you guys here
それならここで皆さんにお見せできます
as soon as they make it
彼らが出来たらすぐに
This is 90 degrees
これは90度です
Afterwards, everyone followed suit and made similar materials.
その後、みんなもそれに倣って同じような資料を作りました。
all these are
これらはすべて
The same series has been here
同じシリーズはこちらにもありました
Of course here we have stopped for many years now
もちろんここでは何年も止まっています
here comes the problem
ここで問題が発生します
where to find
どこで見つけるか
Four temperature operation
4温度動作
But of course this is a very big jump
しかしもちろん、これは非常に大きな飛躍です
jump from here to here
ここからここへジャンプ
the whole situation has changed
全体の状況が変わった
because it immediately has a large impact on the application
すぐにアプリケーションに大きな影響を与えるため、
This is of course our year
もちろん今年は私たちの年です
I have to attend this March Meeting
私はこの 3 月の会議に出席しなければなりません
Everyone is like the wind
誰もが風のような存在
so old man
とても老人
You see, they are all great physicists.
ご存知のとおり、彼らは全員偉大な物理学者です。
this is night
これは夜です
Everyone rush to this special
みんなこのスペシャルに駆けつけてね
Because this is their paper coming out in January
これは1月に発行される彼らの論文だから
This meeting will be held in March
この会議は3月に開催されます
This is the largest open-ended physics meeting of the American Physical Society
これはアメリカ物理学会の最大の無制限の物理学会議です。
There were two to three thousand people at that meeting
その集会には2000人から3000人がいた
Of course it's tens of thousands now
もちろん今は数万です
There are only two or three thousand people for this mission
この仕事に従事できる人員はわずか 2 ～ 3,000 人です
But the waterlines of a few are different
しかし、いくつかの水脈は異なります
That hall is full of people
あのホールは人でいっぱいです
don't sleep at night
夜寝ないでください
stop eating
食べるのをやめる
everyone ran to listen
みんな走って聞いてた
everyone wants
みんなが欲しい
everyone has a speech
みんながスピーチをする
few minutes if you have new results
新しい結果が得られた場合は数分
because they came out
彼らが出てきたから
Everyone hurry back and do it
みんな急いで戻ってやってみろよ
Actually I remember that time
実はその時のことを覚えているんです
I'm doing theory
理論をやってます
Our colleagues
私たちの同僚
We at Virginia Tech
私たちバージニア工科大学
Our colleagues are also burning this material
私たちの同僚もこの物質を燃やしています
everyone is doing
みんながやってる
Let him measure this and that
彼にあれやこれやを測ってもらいましょう
say everyone has to go
みんな行かなきゃって言う
Can't talk for five minutes
5分も話せない
say what we did
私たちが何をしたか言ってください
what did we do
私たちは何をしましたか
what did you measure
何を測定しましたか
There are a lot of people crowded in Allah
アッラーにはたくさんの人が集まっています
You have to listen to this high tide early
この満潮に早く耳を傾けなければなりません
this is a
これは
This is Wuastau
ヴアスタウです
Do you think of this story?
この話について考えますか？
Wuastau this is the concert
ヴアスタウ、これがコンサートです
is an american concert
アメリカのコンサートです
This is Wuastau in physics
これは物理学のヴアスタウです
This situation is hard to find now
この状況は今では見つけるのが困難です
unless you find now
今見つけないと
Lume Time Media Subbattlete
Lume Timeメディアサブバトル
You can Battle
バトルできるよ
Because it's better than this
こっちのほうがいいから
Everyone will be squeezed out
みんな搾り取られるよ
what about this
これはどうですか
Of course this picture is my favorite
もちろんこの写真が一番のお気に入りです
This is Time Magazine
これはタイム誌です
Picture from May 11th
5月11日の写真
Look, wow, I jumped up excitedly
ほら、すごい、興奮して飛び起きた
This temperature keeps going up
この気温は上がり続けています
Say Heating Up
ヒートアップと言う
they are good at writing these
彼らはこれを書くのが上手です
very nice cover
とても素敵なカバー
This is an important breakthrough for them
これは彼らにとって重要な進歩です
Of course there are many applications
もちろん応用もたくさんあります
Let's talk about the various possible applications
考えられるさまざまなアプリケーションについて話しましょう
This is Mueller
ミュラーです
Flocks
群れ
The Mueller two
ミューラー二人
Take the Noble watch to say happy
高貴な時計を持って幸せを伝えましょう
This is what I just said
これは私が今言ったことです
ran here suddenly
突然ここに走って来た
in fact a few years ago
実は数年前に
In 2008 there was another group
2008年には別のグループがあった
temperature high temperature superconducting industry out
高温超電導産業のアウト
This group has the highest temperature
このグループの温度が最も高い
now it's 55 degrees
今は55度です
I'm not just waiting for me to talk
ただ話してくるのを待っているわけではない
still higher
まだ高い
related to this group
このグループに関係する
it's iron
それは鉄です
This is copper
これは銅です
here is iron
ここに鉄があります
The most important element here is copper
ここで最も重要な元素は銅です
The most important element is iron
最も重要な元素は鉄です
This is also strange
これも不思議ですね
Because iron is magnetic
鉄は磁性があるので
how can this be superconducting
どうしてこれが超電導になるのでしょうか
Here are all materials that are not magnetic
磁性を持たない材料はすべてここにあります
all here
全部ここにある
you can watch
あなたは見ることができます
Neither are magnetic materials
どちらも磁性材料ではありません
At that time, it was not possible to use magnetism for angles.
当時は磁気を角度に利用することはできませんでした。
it's here
ここにあります
All of a sudden a complete change
突然完全な変化
This is also magnetic
これも磁石です
so the whole
それで全体
the whole is
全体は
After super-temperature operation, I found a lot of confusion
超高温操作の後、多くの混乱を発見しました
Then let me talk about its application first.
それでは、まずその応用についてお話したいと思います。
I may be a little slow
少し遅いかもしれない
The application I'm going to talk about will be over soon
これから説明するアプリケーションはもうすぐ終了します
Everyone may laugh about the energy crisis
エネルギー危機については誰もが笑うかもしれない
If you can find energy storage materials
エネルギー貯蔵材料が見つかったら
Renewable Energy and Savings
再生可能エネルギーと節約
Don't turn electricity into heat
電気を熱に変えないでください
it will be much better, right?
ずっと良くなりますよね？
We're all turning electricity into heat now
私たちは今、電気を熱に変えています
But the problem is that you need
しかし、問題は、必要なことです
If there is a conductor
指揮者がいる場合
That manipulator can now do a lot of things with magnets
そのマニピュレーターは磁石を使って多くのことができるようになりました
I just said that because it doesn't
そうじゃないからそう言っただけだよ
It does not consume this current
この電流は消費しません
Therefore, a large current can be passed
そのため、大電流を流すことができます
Why couldn't magnets be made before?
なぜ昔は磁石が作れなかったのでしょうか？
What can't be done with this current wire
この電流ワイヤーでは何ができないのか
because you're going to be very hot
とても暑くなるから
So you burn out this one
だからあなたはこれを燃え尽きさせます
So transformer
それで変圧器
almost often the small ones will break
小さなものはほとんどの場合壊れます
Transformers often say
トランスフォーマーはよく言います
Whoa, the transformer exploded.
おっと、変圧器が爆発した。
it's too hot and there's trouble
暑すぎて大変です
That wire is thick
そのワイヤーは太いです
then you start leaking
それから漏れ始めます
trouble
問題
So if you don't have a resistor
したがって、抵抗器がない場合は、
Of course you can put a lot of current
もちろん大電流を流すこともできます
you put the car up
あなたは車を上げました
You can make a cable to pull electricity from the power plant
発電所から電気を引くためのケーブルを作ることができます
Then you can do this MRI
それから、このMRIを行うことができます
This is quantum interference
これが量子干渉です
In fact, you can also do MRI, what is it called?
実はMRIもできるのですが、何と言うのでしょうか？
NMR
NMR
It can also be used as a super disturbance green wave machine
超撹乱グリーンウェーブマシンとしても使用可能
This is an existing product
これは既存の製品です
Super disturbance green wave machine and so on
超妨害グリーンウェーブマシン など
I won't talk much
あまり話さないよ
The main thing is of course
肝心なことはもちろん
like Japan made this stone ax train
日本がこの石斧列車を作ったように
too much to eat
食べすぎます
Its benefit is of course energy saving
メリットはもちろん省エネです
Low noise and high speed can reach 550
低騒音かつ高速は550に達します
This is twice the speed of our high-speed rail
これは高速鉄道の 2 倍の速度です
can reach this speed
このスピードに到達できる
This is the establishment of superconducting Cable in the United States
米国における超電導ケーブルの設立です
for electricity
電気用
They're the latest in Albany, the richest man in New York
彼らはアルバニーの最新鋭であり、ニューヨークで最も裕福な男だ
make this cable
このケーブルを作ります
this is very complicated
これはとても複雑です
high temperature superconductor
高温超電導体
Then pick up this Nitrogen
それからこの窒素を手に取ってください
It's the liquid nitrogen we just mentioned.
それが先ほどお話しした液体窒素です。
in it
初期化
Then there are copper wires outside
それから外には銅線が​​あります
I'm afraid that if something goes wrong
何か問題が起こったら怖いです
Immediately this current is so big
すぐにこの流れはとても大きくなります
it's a big deal
それは大したことだ
so there must be another emergency rescue
それで、もう一度緊急救助をしてください
This is also done with the Koreans
これが韓国人のやることだ
This is the continental superconducting system
これが大陸超電導システムです
The mainland is also doing
本土もやってるよ
Started to make this cable system in 2012
2012年にこのケーブルシステムを作り始めました
business
事業
make this superconducting
これを超電導にする
OK
OK
The whole world is progressing
世界全体が進歩している
Japan also bought an American company
日本もアメリカ企業を買収した
Super Power
スーパーパワー
bought it
買った
and then they
そして彼らは
This is about Power density
これは電力密度についてです
you can get there
そこに着くことができます
It can pull up to 816 meters
最大816メートルまで引き上げることができます
Such a long cable
こんなに長いケーブル
572 amps already
すでに572アンペア
that's big
それは大きいです
Awesome
素晴らしい
has become more and more
ますます多くなりました
This is strong, this line is of course going up
これは強い、このラインはもちろん上がっていく
Of course, the stronger the better, you can pull electricity for several kilometers
もちろん強いほうがいいです、数キロメートルまで電気を引くことができます
And if there are more than 500 arrangements, of course it is a very good transmission system
そして、500以上の配置がある場合、もちろん、それは非常に優れた伝送システムです
So here they have, and there are Korean companies that are also doing this
それで、彼らはこれを持っています、そしてこれは韓国の会社もこれをやっています
So the major countries are doing this
主要国はこれをやっている
The other one is to do non-human energy storage
もう一つは、人間以外のエネルギー貯蔵を行うことです。
Inhumans have actually used it to store energy for a long time
インヒューマンは実際に長い間エネルギーを貯蔵するためにそれを使用してきました
But that object is because you have kinetic energy, because the energy of rotation
しかし、その物体は運動エネルギー、回転エネルギーがあるからです。
You let that thing if there is no friction a thing keeps turning
摩擦がなければ物は回転し続けます
You can treat it as if you turn it faster and faster to transfer energy into it
より速く回転させてエネルギーを伝達するかのように扱うことができます。
When you want to take it out, let it work with a certain
取り出したいときは、ある操作をしてください。
Let it think slowly, let it transfer energy to another
ゆっくり考えさせて、エネルギーを他の人に伝えましょう
As for this non-human being, it is of course better to use the drill now, because there is no friction
この人外の存在については、摩擦がないので、今ドリルを使用する方がもちろん良いです。
So it can do a good job, the first one published by Superpower America
だから、それは良い仕事をすることができます、スーパーパワーアメリカによって出版された最初のもの
Storage now saves energy
ストレージでエネルギーを節約できるようになりました
stored energy is a large
蓄えられたエネルギーは大きい
Staying true to energy is important
エネルギーに忠実であり続けることが重要です
So this is a very important technique
なのでこれはとても重要なテクニックです
Of course you can do what you just said
もちろん、今言ったことを実行することもできます
NMR etc.
NMRなど
you need big magnets
大きな磁石が必要です
Now of course in the collider of the High Energy Experiment
もちろん今は高エネルギー実験の衝突器の中です
They all use super old magnets.
どれも超古い磁石を使用しています。
because it is relatively small
比較的小さいので
but smaller
でも小さい
But its amount and duration are much larger
ただし、その量と期間ははるかに大きくなります
because it has no discretion
裁量権がないから
so much better
良くなったね
of course you have to cool it
もちろん冷やす必要があります
you need a cooling system
冷却システムが必要です
OK but the confusion of high temperature superconductors
わかりましたが、高温超伝導体の混乱
Let's talk about its confusion now
その混乱について今から話しましょう
this all sounds good
これはすべて良さそうです
But we found a lot of strange things
しかし、私たちは奇妙なことをたくさん見つけました
This is a picture we made ourselves
これは私たちが自分たちで作った写真です
I asked my postdoc to go and look up those things
私はポスドクにそれらのことを調べに行くように頼んだ
what does this picture mean
この絵は何を意味しますか
This is its superconducting transition temperature
これは超伝導転移温度です
with it at room temperature right now
このまま室温で
If you measure its resistivity
抵抗率を測ってみると
you take log
あなたはログを取ります
Because the number is far from
数字が遠いので
many times
何度も
So with this scheme, the difference is 10 to the power of one
したがって、このスキームでは、その差は 10 の累乗になります。
This is 10 to the power of -1
これは 10 の -1 乗です
This 10 to the power of -2
この 10 の -2 乗
Resistivity
抵抗率
Then you can see these new
そうすれば、これらの新しいものを見ることができます
superconducting iron
超電導鉄
all in this paragraph
この段落のすべて
are high resistivity
抵抗率が高い
But they usually also have a higher TC
しかし、通常は TC も高くなります
But this one is old like quicksilver
しかし、これはクイックシルバーのように古いです
The 23 degrees mentioned just now are all here
さっき言った23度は全部ここにある
TC is lower here
ここのTCは比較的低いです
But its resistivity is very low at room temperature
しかし、その抵抗率は室温では非常に低いです
means it's a good metal
それは良い金属であることを意味します
You measure it at room temperature and say these are good metals
室温で測定して、これは良い金属だと言います
these are bad metal
これらは悪い金属です
Later found another MGB2
その後、別の MGB2 が見つかりました
See it is the same as the old one
見てください、古いものと同じです
Its resistivity is also very low
抵抗率も非常に低いです
just at room temperature
ちょうど室温で
These are good conductors
彼らは良い指揮者です
can be used for normal
通常に使用できます
the same wire or something
同じワイヤーか何か
this is very good
これはすごくいい
But this is all bad
しかし、これはすべて悪いです
Here's a weirder one
ここにもっと奇妙なものがあります
very complicated
とても難しい
This is called organic
これをオーガニックといいます
organic superconductor
有機超電導体
Stranger and Larger Molecules
見知らぬより大きな分子
very complicated
とても難しい
This is also very resistive
これもかなり抵抗あるな
But the temperature is also around 20 degrees
でも気温も20度くらいあります
So it's kind of weird
だからそれはちょっと奇妙です
Usually we think
通常私たちはこう考えます
More conductive metals should be better at superconducting
導電性の高い金属ほど超電導性が優れているはずです
that was the old idea
それは古い考えでした
BCS also predicts like this
BCSもこう予想
But now I find that this kind of new ones are not
しかし今では、この種の新しいものはそうではないことがわかりました
It's a bad resistor
不良抵抗です
very bad
ひどい
On the contrary, superconducting temperature is very high
逆に、超電導温度は非常に高い
this is strange
これはおかしい
The other is that these are bilingual systems
もう 1 つは、これらはバイリンガル システムであるということです
is copper
銅です
You see copper is a plane
銅は平面であることがわかります
another plane
別の飛行機
another circle
別のサークル
The main superconductivity is in the copper plane
主な超伝導は銅面にあります
The main superconductivity is in the iron plane
主な超伝導は鉄面にある
most
大部分
They all look like two-dimensional systems when their electrons move
電子が動くとそれらはすべて二次元システムのように見えます
It's not three-dimensional, so it's very different from before
立体的ではないので今までとは大きく違います
some features of this
これのいくつかの特徴
Something else weird is that these superconducting states
他に奇妙な点は、これらの超伝導状態が
If you dope you can make it superconducting or not superconducting
ドープすれば超電導にも非超電導にもできる
But it's all similar to this magnetic
でもそれはすべてこの磁力に似ています
This phase diagram is if I put different numbers to replace a certain atom
この状態図は、ある原子を別の番号で置き換えた場合の状態図です。
If silk is used instead of blue, if it is replaced by a little
ブルーの代わりにシルクを使ったら、少し置き換えれば
The more I replace, the more I become superconducting
交換すればするほど超電導になる
Instead of a little I am antiferromagnetic
少しではなく、私は反強磁性体です
is magnetic
磁性がある
Upper wisdom and lower wisdom are ranked
上位の知恵と下位の知恵はランク付けされます
one up next next up
一個上一個下一個上一下
It is equal to the blue, red, blue and red gold grids arranged well
青、赤、青、赤の金の格子がうまく配置されているのと同じです
a square square
正方形の正方形
Next to your blue is red
あなたの青の隣は赤です
blue next to red
赤の隣に青
This is a well-arranged antiferromagnetic
これはよく配置された反強磁性体です
But if you put a little more in it, it becomes superconducting
でももう少し入れると超電導になる
But it's so close
でも、とても近いです
Another point is that the product superconductivity of iron is the same
もう一つのポイントは、鉄の製品超電導性は同じであるということです。
they have many similarities
彼らには多くの類似点があります
But this is a phenomenon that the old superconductors did not have before.
しかし、これは古い超電導体にはなかった現象です。
The farther away they are from persistence the better
永続性から遠ざかるほど良い
So there is no persistent material
したがって持続的な素材はありません
But this persistence is quite high
しかしこの持続力はかなり高い
The sustaining temperature is actually quite high, 300 degrees here
維持温度は実際には非常に高く、ここでは300度です
so strong persistence
とても強い持続力
But instead a very high superconducting temperature
しかし、その代わりに非常に高い超伝導温度が発生します。
this is very strange
これはとても奇妙です
This is the Waterfall team I was talking about
これが私が話していたウォーターフォールチームです
don't like holding sex
セックスをするのが好きではない
What did you do, persistent
どうしたんだ、しつこい
The organic superconductivity just mentioned
先ほどの有機超電導
also near here
ここの近くにもあります
All the shopkeepers around here have poor sight temperatures
この辺の店主はみんな視力が低いです
don't even think about it
それについても考えないでください
because it has persistence in it
そこには持続力があるから
bumping, bumping, bumping
ぶつかる、ぶつかる、ぶつかる
so it doesn't like
だからそれは好きじゃない
But its superconducting temperature is very high
しかし、その超伝導温度は非常に高い
Of course everyone thinks about it
もちろんみんな思ってるよ
how do i solve this problem
この問題をどうやって解決すればいいですか
How can I help form a CooporPair
CooporPair の形成を支援するにはどうすればよいですか
Coopor team
クーパーチーム
possible communication we have already talked about reproduction
可能性のあるコミュニケーション 生殖についてはすでに話しました
Of course everyone wants to do theory
もちろん誰もが理論をやりたいと思っています
Of course you can sit at home and think a lot
もちろん家に座っていろいろ考えることもできます
We also did this plasma
このプラズマもやりました
Plasma
プラズマ
You don't understand, it means you have a lot of batteries
理解できないのは、バッテリーがたくさんあるということです
Because positively charged ions are on the grid
正に帯電したイオンがグリッド上にあるため
Then you have electrons that can run around and it can go the right way
そうすれば電子が走り回って正しい方向に進むことができる
Collective Righteous Way It is not just one or two electricity, many electric righteousness
集団的正義の道 それは一つや二つの電気ではなく、多くの電気の正義です
Of course, if there is the right way, there will be more batteries here.
もちろん、正しい方法があれば、ここにはさらに多くのバッテリーがあります。
There is less battery over there, less battery looks like righteousness
あそこはバッテリーが少ない、バッテリーが少ないのが正義のように見える
Positive and multi-battery, this kind of positive way can also cause two batteries
プラスとマルチバッテリー、この種のプラスの方法では、バッテリーが2つになる可能性もあります
Of course, this has never been found. This is a theory that is often said.
もちろん、これは見つかったわけではなく、よく言われる説です。
And then there's another one that we notice because electrons also have a magnetic moment
そして、電子にも磁気モーメントがあるので、もう一つ気がつくことがあります。
We just mentioned that there is a magnetic whirl, so we have the body just mentioned
磁気の渦があると先ほど述べたので、先ほど述べた体があります。
Everything uses the force of cool people because it uses electric charges
全ては電荷を使うからカッコいい人の力を使うんだよ
We did not talk about the influence of the magnetic moment, if there is a magnetic moment
磁気モーメントがある場合、磁気モーメントの影響については話しませんでした。
It can also work by itself, just the magnetic force of the magnetic wire is working
マグネットワイヤーの磁力だけで動作するため、単独で動作することもできます。
It doesn't have to rely on the effect of charge, so there are other possibilities.
チャージの効果に頼る必要はないので、他にも可能性はあります。
Then this is what I just said about high temperature exceeding the body. We just talked about it.
それから、これは先ほど私が申し上げた、人体を超える高温についてです。
This is the super-body mentioned by Naobiao.
これがナオビアオの言うスーパーボディだ。
Replaced a little bit with back heel silk
バックヒールシルクに少し交換
If not it's as simple as
そうでない場合は、次のように簡単です
very nice a jingle
とても素敵なジングル
well arranged
よく整えられた
The red inside is copper
内側の赤い部分は銅です
next to copper is oxygen
銅の次は酸素です
Below the middle is a large pile of this blue or stone
真ん中の下には、この青または石の大きな山があります
Blue if you want Ginger not
ジンジャーを望まない場合はブルー
That's copper oxide again
それはまた酸化銅です
Copper Oxygen Plane Again
再び銅の酸素飛行機
if so
もしそうなら
I drew all the copper planes
銅版は全部描きました
it is each with a word string
それぞれ単語列が付いています
This is the anti-iron pool I just mentioned
これが先ほど言った抗鉄プールです
one up one down one up one down
一上一下一上一下
Well lined up
ちゃんと並んでる
This is its anti-iron pool
これがその抗鉄プールです
But in fact we remember
しかし実際には私たちは覚えています
We are in a quantum world
私たちは量子の世界にいます
Quantum doesn't like things that don't move
クォンタムは動かないものを嫌います
Didn't I say it just now?
今言ったじゃないですか？
it doesn't like you not moving
あなたが動かないのが気に入らない
High energy due to motionless
静止しているため高エネルギー
This sea cucumber treasure is not sure how far away
このナマコの宝物はどれくらい遠くにあるのかわかりません
so what does it do
それで、それは何をするのですか
It still needs to exchange the two
まだ2つを交換する必要があります
You can imagine everyone doing row after row
みんなが次から次へとやっていることを想像できるだろう
Well done Blue Red Blue Red Ginger
よくやったブルーレッドブルーレッドジンジャー
Swap the blue one with the red one
青と赤を交換してください
exchange over there again
もう一度あそこで交換してください
swap it and swap it back
交換して元に戻します
just keep swapping
交換し続けるだけ
it swaps to go , but an average of one-fifth swaps again
go にスワップしますが、平均 5 分の 1 が再びスワップします
If you take a photo at any time, about one-fifth of it is an exchange
いつでも写真を撮ったら5分の1くらいが交換
But most of them are in the right place
しかし、それらのほとんどは正しい場所にあります
This is probably the state when it is half full.
おそらく半分まで入った状態です。
This is because of quantum effects, making it exchange
これは量子効果によるもので、交換が行われます。
This exchange is like what you just said, think about it, it's like red
このやり取りはあなたが今言ったようなものです、考えてみてください、それは赤いようなものです
but it can't run very far
でもあまり遠くまでは走れない
because it's coming back soon
もうすぐ戻ってくるから
It's in the wrong place, the energy is a little higher
間違った場所にある、エネルギーは少し高い
so it likes to come back, after a while it jumps back
だから戻ってくるのが好きで、しばらくすると飛び跳ねて戻ってくる
But it's not okay to stay still, so it jumps around
でも、じっとしているのはダメで、飛び跳ねます。
This is a very simple quantum action
これは非常に単純な量子アクションです
Now if we use back or silk instead
代わりにバックまたはシルクを使用すると、
There were originally three blue planes, but two on the back
もともとブルーは3つあったのですが、後ろに2つあります
So it has one less electron
つまり電子が1個少ない
So there are fewer electrons in it.
したがって、その中の電子は少なくなります。
The same surface suddenly lost an electron
同じ表面が突然電子を失いました
It means that there is a hole, that is, the electron is removed.
正孔が存在する、つまり電子が抜けていることを意味します。
it has an extra hole
余分な穴があります
that's even better
それはさらに良いです
Because he just said he doesn't like to stop there
なぜなら彼はそこで止まりたくないと言ったからです
He just jumps right into the hole now
彼は今まさに穴に飛び込みます
He has one more, the emperor can jump to the vacant seat
彼にはもう一つある、皇帝は空いた席に飛びつくことができる
So as soon as you have a void
だから空白ができたらすぐに
He started to play a little more role
彼はもう少し役割を果たし始めた
In addition to electron up-spin down-spin exchange
電子のアップスピン、ダウンスピンの交換に加えて
he can jump with holes
彼は穴があいてもジャンプできる
he keeps jumping
彼は飛び跳ね続けます
This jump is great
このジャンプはすごいですね
Because of jumping, this arrangement is gone.
ジャンプしたせいでこの配置はなくなってしまいました。
As you can imagine, there are a lot of vacancies now
ご想像のとおり、現在空室がたくさんあります
If you are a blue building and the next door is red
あなたが青い建物で隣が赤い建物なら
You are now asking you to change chairs
あなたは今、椅子を変えるよう求めています
It won't be a mess after a while
しばらくすれば混乱することはない
All of a sudden, the neatly arranged golden grids disappeared.
突然、整然と並んだ金色の格子が消えた。
gone soon
すぐになくなった
Of course it was broken up with this
もちろんこれで解散しました
He can move around again
彼は再び動き回ることができる
Now the team can
今、チームはできること
not only in the original place
元の場所だけでなく
It turns out that you are all near
あなたはみんな近くにいることがわかりました
I can run far now
今は遠くまで走れるよ
this team can run
このチームは走れる
This dry foil team starts again
ドライフォイルチームが再始動
like the one i just said
私が今言ったことのように
The situation where the dance was drawn
ダンスが描かれた様子
he can run far
彼は遠くまで走れる
because now there are
今はあるから
If there is a hole, you can't run far without a hole, and if there is a hole, it's easy to run
穴があっても穴がなければ遠くまで走れない、穴があれば走りやすい
This spaced one, this adjacent one, this one because of fanning
この間隔のあるもの、この隣接するもの、これは煽りによるもの
So there isn't such a strong force to keep him in the same position
つまり、彼を同じ位置に維持するほど強い力はありません
so he can run around
彼が走り回れるように
Then dance with the Cooper team that we were talking about
それから、私たちが話していたクーパーチームと一緒に踊ります
Come to think of it, it's actually very close
考えてみれば、本当に近いですね
It doesn't make a difference because he's doing the same thing
やってることは同じだから何も変わらないよ
One up, one down, one up and one down exchange over there
あそこで1つ上、1つ下、1つ上と1つ下の交換
he is going to run
彼は走るつもりだ
That, that, that, when he said it like this, it would be resolved, it was the reason for the guidance
あれ、あれ、こう言えば解決するって指導の理由だったんだ
Of course it's not that simple, because if you take a closer look
もちろん、それほど単純ではありません。詳しく見てみると、
He still has a lot to crawl, but I don't talk about so much confusion today
彼にはまだ這うべきことがたくさんあるが、今日はあまり混乱については話さない
He has a lot of confusion, if you look carefully at any time, you will be confused
彼はたくさんの混乱を抱えています、いつでも注意深く見ていると、あなたは混乱するでしょう
There is a very important experiment, which is the reason for the development of Naimi Technology
Naimi Technology の開発のきっかけとなった非常に重要な実験があります。
I just invented this, this, that is a picture number I copied from someone else’s online inspection
これ、これ、これは、他の人のオンライン検査からコピーした画像番号です。
This is called Scanning internally my...
これは内部的にスキャンと呼ばれています...
scanning through sleep microscope
睡眠顕微鏡によるスキャン
it has a very real extension
非常に現実的な拡張子があります
This is your original sample
これはあなたのオリジナルサンプルです
If you add a little bit of voltage to the current
電流に少し電圧を加えると
There are electrons that wear and sleep from here
ここから着て眠る電子がある
what can this do
これで何ができるの
can measure its height
高さを測ることができる
each of which can be measured
それぞれ測定可能
In particular, different electron densities are different
特に、異なる電子密度は異なります
it can measure anything
それは何でも測定できます
This is called STM
これをSTMといいます
叫Scanning internally micro
×内部マイクロスキャン
This is the work that won the Nobel Prize
これはノーベル賞を受賞した作品です
The whole nanotechnology starts here
ナノテクノロジー全体がここから始まります
Then if you read what I just said
それで、私が今言ったことを読んでいただければ、
High temperature superconducting samples
高温超電導サンプル
You see what it measures
何を測定するかがわかります
under the same voltage
同じ電圧下で
This current is very uneven
この電流は非常に不均一です
If you look closely, it is very uneven
よく見るとかなり凹凸がある
It's a bit like we're uneven here
ここはちょっと不均一な気がする
very messy
非常に厄介
the one i was talking about
私が話していたこと
Ordinary superconductors are different
普通の超電導体は違う
Normal superconductors are perfect
通常の超伝導体は完璧です
This is superconducting too cool
超電導かっこよすぎる
it's very uneven
とても不均一です
Then carefully put this into these ten nanometers
それからこれを慎重にこの10ナノメートルに入れます
you make it bigger
あなたはそれを大きくします
This is only four nanometers
これはわずか4ナノメートルです
Zoom in again
もう一度ズームイン
it looks at every atom
それはあらゆる原子を観察します
every copper atom
すべての銅原子
between two atoms
2つの原子の間
you are uneven
あなたは不均一です
this is incredible this measurement
この測定値は信じられないほどです
we have a colleague now
私たちには今同僚がいます
There are ways to measure more like this
このようにさらに測定する方法があります
This makes its measurement
これにより測定が行われます
measure out
測る
These are uneven
これらは不均一です
Electrons are not uniform in this
この場合、電子は均一ではありません
This is like the dance I just mentioned
これは先ほど言ったダンスに似ています
there's more in dancing
ダンスにはもっとたくさんのことがあります
more complicated
より複雑
here's this jump time
これがジャンプタイムです
There is a group of people walking to the left
左側に歩いてくる集団がいる
There is a group of that Couple going to the right
右に行くカップルのグループがいます
So I will think a lot here
そこで、ここでいろいろ考えてみます
less here
ここでは少ない
Just started everyone has updated shots
始まったばかりですが、全員がショットを更新しました
Not only did it jump like this
このようにジャンプしただけではありません
It also has a certain mutual motion with each other
また、互いに一定の相互運動を持っています
that's what you can imagine
それはあなたが想像できることです
Some earth dances are so complicated
いくつかのアースダンスはとても複雑です
Jumping is so complicated
ジャンプはとても複雑です
This electron does complicated things
この電子は複雑なことをする
it's still uneven
まだ不均一です
It's in Cao Daotai, so this is very novel
曹道台にあるのでとても斬新です
This is the old one from the past, it is the traditional Caodao, and it is completely non-existent
これは過去の古いものであり、伝統的な曹島であり、まったく存在しません
Impossible things are here
不可能なものがここにある
It started to have various variations again
また色々なバリエーションが出るようになりました
This is what I just mentioned above
これは先ほど上で述べたものです
When the force is very strong, the force here is of course very strong
力が非常に強いとき、ここの力も当然非常に強いです
The force of Kuren is very strong, this is a very strange thing
クレンの力はとても強い、これはとても不思議なことだ
The strong Kuren force has a very high Caodao temperature
強力なクレン軍は非常に高い曹島温度を持っています
That's the complete opposite, completely different from what we usually imagine
それは真逆であり、私たちが通常想像しているものとはまったく異なります
So in the bcs theory here is a big problem
つまり、bcs理論ではここに大きな問題があります
Now everyone believes that probably the bcs theory cannot explain this phenomenon
今ではおそらくbcs理論ではこの現象を説明できないと誰もが信じています。
The main reason is that there is complexity
主な理由は複雑さである
Far beyond this simplest theory
この最も単純な理論をはるかに超えています
So this is why we have been studying this for so many years
これが私たちがこれを何年も研究してきた理由です
Now we understand that the electricity and number of this are different here
ここで、この電気と数が異なることがわかりました
everything is different
すべてが違う
We haven’t measured this until the experiment. We can tell him that it’s different.
私たちは実験するまでこれを測定していませんでしたが、彼にそれが違うことを伝えることができました。
Now let's finally talk about higher superconducting temperatures.
さて、いよいよ超伝導温度の高さについて話しましょう。
There are several possibilities, one is to find new materials
可能性はいくつかありますが、その 1 つは新しい素材を見つけることです。
Then this is a new one just mentioned, this is actually just now
それから、これは今言及した新しいものです、これは実際に今のものです
This is the first quick delivery made by Academician Wu Maokun.
呉茂坤院士による初めての短納期です。
People develop it into a plane
人々はそれを飛行機に発展させます
This is an incredible technique on one material
これは一つの素材を使った素晴らしいテクニックです
I don’t know how to say this in Chinese Stranding Titanium Oxide
中国語で何と言えばいいのかわかりません。
On top of this material, grow a layer on a very thin material
この材料の上に、非常に薄い材料の層を成長させます
It is one layer of iron and T, iron and C, one layer of iron C
鉄とTの一層、鉄とC、鉄の一層Cです
Then they measure the superconducting temperature, there are many papers
それから超電導温度を測定する、多くの論文がある
It came out in this journal that the superconducting temperature should reach 100
超伝導温度は100℃に達するはずだということがこの雑誌に載った
09 degrees
09度
it must be shaken to death
それは死ぬほど揺さぶられなければならない
But 65 degrees is probably no problem.
でも65度ならおそらく問題ないでしょう。
109 degrees will shock you to death
109度だとショック死するよ
But that temperature is only 8 degrees higher than the original temperature of this thing
しかし、その温度はこの物の元の温度よりわずか8度高いだけです
It's time to make a wish without fainting
気を失わずに願いを叶える時が来た
That temperature is only 8 degrees
その気温はたったの8度です
Now people use this method
現在、人々はこの方法を使用しています
When it is not the same as it is made
作ったものと違う場合
why?
なぜ？
that may be new physics on this surface
それはこの地表における新しい物理学かもしれない
This is the mechanism we just disturbed
これが私たちがたった今妨害したメカニズムです
This is what experiments tell us
これが実験で分かることです
The temperature here is much, much higher than before.
ここの気温は以前よりもはるかに高いです。
This mechanism may not be the original
この仕組みはオリジナルではないかもしれません
Then it has a new possibility
そうすれば新たな可能性が生まれる
that's certainly possible
それは確かに可能です
Because it is possible that the biomass here has a great influence on it
ここのバイオマスが大きく影響している可能性があるので
But here the biomass influence is very large causing this electron
しかし、ここではバイオマスの影響が非常に大きく、この電子が発生します。
because it is compartment
コンパートメントなので
The electron is still here
電子はまだここにある
So I didn't trap it very hard
だから私はそれをあまり難しく捕らえませんでした
Didn't dig it deep just now
今は深く掘り下げてませんでした
so it can run fast
それで速く走れるようになります
But electrons are strong
でも電子は強い
So it is possible that its superconducting temperature increases
したがって、超伝導温度が上昇する可能性があります
This lead is a hot end of term doing research
このリードは研究を行っている学期末の熱い時期です
You can see that this paper is very popular at the end of the term
この論文は期末に非常に人気があることがわかります
This guide pull is an interesting idea
このガイドプルは面白いアイデアですね
Some people have thought about using this interface to control
このインターフェイスを使用して制御することを考えている人もいます。
an electron in a layer
層内の電子
that rope is on another layer
そのロープは別のレイヤーにあります
or positively charged on another layer
または別の層で正に帯電する
Your negative charge is on another layer
あなたのマイナス電荷は別の層にあります
How to control? This Nimi technology is here
どう制御するか?このNimiテクノロジーがここにあります
We can now control the material
素材をコントロールできるようになりました
Think of ways to make a variety of such interfaces to
このようなさまざまなインターフェースを作成する方法を考えてください。
This can also increase the operating temperature
これにより動作温度も上昇する可能性があります
Another more exciting thing is that under high pressure
もう 1 つ興味深いのは、高圧下でのことです。
Just now we said that increasing the high pressure is a
先ほど、高圧を上げることは重要であると言いました。
But this high pressure is as high as 200GP
しかしこの高圧は200GPにも達します
There are only a few in the world
世界に数個しかない
Someone use this ability to do this high pressure
誰かがこの能力を使ってこの高圧的なことをする
The person who mainly made this
主にこれを作った人
I used to do a post with that Wang Heguangyuan
私は以前、王和光源さんと記事を書いていました
Aremes
アレメス
they recently discovered
彼らは最近発見した
Everyone thinks of Liu Huaqing smelling bad
劉華清は臭いと誰もが思っている
In Jiang Mishan, you may often smell some
江密山では、よく匂いがするかもしれません。
This is of course poisonous proof
これはもちろん毒の証拠です
not good
良くない
very bad gas
非常に悪いガス
this is fine now
これでもう大丈夫です
Squeeze the shit out of it
たわごとを絞り出してください
Physicists are crazy
物理学者は頭がおかしい
Of course it makes sense
もちろんそれは理にかなっています
squeeze it down
それを押し下げる
He said 200 shower 3 degrees
彼は 200 シャワー 3 度と言った
Oops
おっと
Of course if he's proven right
もちろん彼が正しいことが証明されれば
This is the job Noble talked about again.
これがノーブルが再び話した仕事です。
But this problem is difficult to prove
しかし、この問題を証明するのは難しい
Because few people have 200
200持ってる人は少ないから
Gagapet kettle
ガガペットケトル
This instrument and especially complex
この楽器は特に複雑です
he does
彼はやる
This is of course an early theory
もちろんこれは初期の理論です
let me talk about theory
理論について話しましょう
Anyway, it doesn't cost anything
とにかくお金はかかりません
Said that maybe in such a material
たぶんそのような素材で言った
Kiyomi
清美
Because everyone thinks clearly
みんなしっかり考えてるから
So vibrate so much
とても振動します
high frequency of vibration
高周波の振動
Farmers’ comments are also very high, which is related to the BCS theory just mentioned
農民のコメントも非常に高く、これは先ほどの BCS 理論に関連しています。
It is easy to operate and the temperature will increase
操作が簡単で温度も上がります
That is what I want to say, if farmers are not orthodox, they must not operate
私が言いたいのは、農家が正統でなければ農業をやってはいけないということです。
The more orthodox, the better
オーソドックスであればあるほど良い
The higher the comment, the better
コメントが高いほど良い
So very early on Prediction said
非常に早い段階で予測はこう言いました
Theoretically speaking, it’s more than three hundred. Of course, no one believes it when they come here often
理論的には300以上だ。もちろん、頻繁にここに来る人は誰も信じないだろう
How could it be more than 200 or 300 to do this job?
この仕事をするのにどうして 200 人や 300 人以上もかかるのでしょうか?
But these they do, of course I don't know if this is this
でも、彼らはそうしている、もちろん、これがこれなのかどうかは分からない
Of course this is, because everyone knows that it is easy for electrons to escape
もちろん、電子が逃げやすいことは誰でも知っているからです。
But it is also easy to become H-minor, there are two electrons coming
しかし、Hマイナーになることも簡単です、電子が2つ来ます
one more electron
もう一つの電子
So it's kind of like Cooper Pet
クーパーペットみたいな感じですね
From here to here there is a couple
ここからここまでカップルがいます
so this is interesting
これは面白いですね
Is there an extra physics
追加の物理演算はありますか
Not so simple physics
それほど単純な物理学ではない
Of course this has not been confirmed
もちろんこれは確認されていません
I'm just talking, that is to say, I have some new ideas
私はただ話しているだけです、つまり、いくつかの新しいアイデアがあります
That is, if we find a stronger force
つまり、より強い力を見つけた場合
It is not necessary to say that we cannot
必ずしもできないとは言えません
But of course how do you prevent what I just said
しかしもちろん、私が今言ったことをどうやって防ぐことができますか
nothing else to add
他に追加することはありません
because you tied it too tight
きつく縛りすぎたから
It's simple and it's not too tight
シンプルなのでかっちりしすぎず、
Because the person itself will vibrate very much
人自体がとても振動するので
so maybe not tied too tight
だからあまりきつく縛らないほうがいいかもしれない
It's hard to tie a kiss too tight
キスをきつく結ぶのは難しい
because it is very light
とても軽いので
So the problem is under this
したがって、問題はこの下にあります
There may also be other operators
他のオペレーターもいるかもしれない
Of course you will often see it in newspapers
確かに新聞でもよく見かけますよね
And who found another operator
そして、他のオペレーターを見つけたのは誰ですか
this will be a lot
これはたくさんあるだろう
we used to joke a lot
私たちはよく冗談を言っていた
this is called
これは呼ばれます
We are called UFO and everyone knows that
私たちはUFOと呼ばれ、誰もがそれを知っています
Unidentified Flying Object
ユーフォー
It's just an unidentified flying object.
ただの未確認飛行物体です。
what is flying
何が飛んでいるのか
We often say that this superconducting world also has
この超電導の世界にも、
USO Unidentified Superconducting Object
USO未確認超電導物体
superconducting
超電導
many people posted
多くの人が投稿しました
i see 300 degrees
300度が見えます
I saw 200 for a while
しばらく200を見ました
head pass
ヘッドパス
haven't found it for so many years
何年も見つからなかった
But of course there is some evidence here
しかし、もちろんここにはいくつかの証拠があります
Some of its rugs still look obvious
敷物の一部はまだはっきりと見えます
But it's obviously early. Why on earth?
でも明らかに早いのに、一体なぜ？
I don't know if it's really too high
本当に高すぎるかどうかはわかりません
But this question
しかし、この質問は
Lume Temporary called this dream
この夢をルーム・テンポラリーと呼んだ
i think we'll always have
いつでもあると思います
I thank you all for this
皆さんに感謝します
I also thank my assistants
アシスタントの方々にも感謝です
Professor Chen Yingqian gave me a lot of slides
Chen Yingqian 教授がたくさんのスライドをくれました
Principal Wu Maokun gave me some slides
ウー・マオクン校長がスライドをくれました
but thanks for their help
しかし、彼らの助けに感謝します
thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました
Okay, thank you
大丈夫ありがとう
well timed
タイミングよく
good
良い
you
あなた
Do you have any questions?
何か質問がありますか？
or
また
please
お願いします
Thank you teacher for a very wonderful speech
先生、とても素晴らしいお話をありがとうございました
Let me first admit that I am a student of biology
まず最初に認めさせてください、私は生物学の学生です
so
それで
I don't really understand the details
詳細はよくわかりません
but in my mind
でも私の心の中では
I used to send
以前送ってた
It has been said since the beginning of the year
今年の初めから言われてた
start as a single atomic material
単一の原子物質として始まる
Later, it gradually became multi-atomic
その後、徐々に多原子化しました
In my impression, at that super high temperature
私の印象では、あの超高温で
When the super-heated high temperature jumps
過熱した高温が跳ね上がるとき
It seems to have been predicted
予言されてたような気がする
the composite material
複合材料
Is the atom in it replaced by which one?
その中の原子はどれに置き換えられますか?
it may become high temperature
高温になる可能性があります
Then it was math
後は数学でした
Forget it, which element may be extrapolated later
忘れてください。どの要素は後で推定される可能性があります
The substitution was successful.
置換は成功しました。
That's especially new from what you introduced today
それは今日紹介したものから特に新しいことです
Two cases in 2015
2015年二例
that's what i think
それが私が思うことです
i think at that time
その時思う
Of course they're a bit disrespectful
もちろん彼らは少し失礼です
This is quite a lot
これはかなり多いです
The blue quilt is the same one that won the Nobel Prize
青いキルトはノーベル賞を受賞したものと同じです
he is not for this reason
彼はそういう理由ではない
His reason is not calculation
彼の理由は打算ではない
His idea was to increase the effect of electroplasma
彼のアイデアはエレクトロプラズマの効果を高めることでした
he knows this
彼はこれを知っています
usually this
通常はこれ
These are ceramic materials weird
これらは奇妙なセラミック素材です
I just talked about these new high temperatures
先ほど、新たな高温についてお話しました。
The Blue Bell of Taobao body is the same
タオバオ本体のブルーベルも同じです
Mao Kun Zhu Jin Weapon
茂昆朱金武器
they found out
彼らは知った
ceramic material is very fragile
セラミック素材は非常に壊れやすい
That's what you can't imagine saying
それはあなたが言うとは想像できないことです
it becomes superconducting
超電導になる
but he made it superconducting
しかし彼はそれを超電導にした
So they know that there are electric
それで彼らは電気があることを知っています
So the original Bandau's Mule was for electric birth to many people
つまり、オリジナルのバンダウ・ラバは多くの人に電気を産むためのものだった
He did it to see if the temperature was up to
彼は気温が最高かどうかを確認するためにそれをした
As a result, he found that the temperature was very high
その結果、気温が非常に高いことが分かりました。
Of course, now we know that he has nothing to do with the effect of electrogenesis
もちろん、彼が電気発生の影響とは何の関係もないことはわかっています。
It's not for that reason that it becomes over
だから超になるわけではない
but usually the right answer for the wrong reasons
しかし、たいていの場合、正しい答えには間違った理由がある
That's okay too
それも大丈夫です
This is what science is all about.
これが科学のすべてです。
Then he is single, you just talked about calculating
それから彼は独身です、あなたはちょうど計算について話しました
In fact, many people have calculated many materials and said that the temperature is very high
実際、多くの人が多くの材料を計算し、温度が非常に高いと述べています。
Experiments that were wrong at first proved to be wrong
最初は間違っていた実験が間違っていたことが判明
we are not right yet
私たちはまだ正しくありません
So I just said the last one, I don’t know if it’s right
だから最後に言ったけど、それが正しいかどうかは分からない
Most of them are 99% wrong
それらのほとんどは99％間違っています
what you imagine is not real
あなたが想像しているものは現実ではありません
Yeah, I want to ask this too
はい、これも聞きたいです
Because that microscope that just looked at that tunnel
だってあのトンネルを観察したばかりのあの顕微鏡だから
It looks like another rule
別のルールのようです
You also mentioned that it may have another physical law
別の物理法則があるかもしれないともおっしゃっていましたね
In fact, it is not clear
実際のところは明らかではない
have what
何がある
another physical phenomenon
別の物理現象
That is, can these be described by mathematics?
つまり、これらは数学で説明できるのでしょうか？
I think the extrapolated way
推定された方法だと思います
is described by mathematics
数学で説明される
you don't really quantify
あなたは実際に数値化していない
Then you can't really predict
そうなると本当に予測できなくなります
Many experiments are useless
多くの実験は役に立たない
theory is to quantify
理論は数値化することです
It is useful to predict
予測するのに便利です
So all the talking things have to be spread out
だから、話すことはすべて広げなければならない
only useful
役に立つだけ
so must
そうしなければならない
so even though
だからたとえ
I talked about such a miraculous quantum state
そんな奇跡の量子状態についてお話しました
macroscopic quantum state
巨觀量子態
Giants are rare
巨人は珍しい
Then this is beyond
じゃあこれは超えてるよ
If in the test
テスト中の場合
I say this
私はこう言います
so it's a big deal
だからそれは大したことだよ
because only
なぜなら、ただ
Only after sniffing our little quantum mechanics
私たちの小さな量子力学の匂いを嗅いだ後にのみ
should not be very important
あまり重要ではないはずです
Then if there is a huge amount
それで量が多ければ
Of course it's a great thing
もちろんそれは素晴らしいことだ
this is difficult
これは難しいです
Because the quantum state must
なぜなら、量子状態は
should be kept at a very low temperature
非常に低い温度で保管する必要があります
small size
小さいサイズ
but now it's about
でも今はそれについてです
It was a big size just now
先ほどは大きいサイズでした
you have seen
あなたは見たことがあります
The performance of the quantum state
量子状態のパフォーマンス
This is likely to have more
これはもっと増える可能性が高い
So we wish to find the temperature
それで温度を知りたいのです
All four temperatures are superconducting
4つの温度はすべて超伝導です
You have to reheat it so it doesn't superconduct
超電導にならないように再加熱する必要がある
this is dream
これは夢です
It would be a very good thing if it came out
出てきたらすごくいいことになるよ
This is still difficult
これはまだ難しいです
There are a lot more
他にもたくさんあります
Of course it is because of difficulties
もちろん困難があるからです
we have research to do
私たちにはやるべき研究がある
please
お願いします
ask the professor
教授に聞く
The one that just experimented with the one that floated
浮かんだものを試しただけのもの
It's also called the principle of Chifu
知風の原理とも言います。
Yes or no
はい、もしくは、いいえ
right
右
Excuse me, the rotten train in Japan that you just introduced
すみません、先ほど紹介した日本の腐った電車です
this is the principle
これが原則です
So that means their train is running
つまり、彼らの列車は走っているということです
Will there be a lot of smoke?
煙がたくさん出ますか？
No
いいえ
certainly
そうです
we can't help it
それは仕方がありません
if we cover you up
私たちがあなたを隠したら
Then put another train on top of it
そしてその上に別の電車を乗せます
Toys can be compared and analyzed like this
おもちゃはこんな感じで比較・分析できます
Put another toy on top
上に別のおもちゃを置きます
You can't see the train from above
上からは電車が見えない
just sealed it up inside
中に閉じ込めただけ
that liquid doesn't evaporate
その液体は蒸発しない
it has a cooling system all closed
冷却システムが完全に密閉されています
This way it will last longer
こうすれば長持ちしますよ
This cooling system
この冷却システムは
So probably save this
だからおそらくこれを保存します
it keeps it sealed
それは密封された状態を保ちます
you can't see the smoke
煙は見えません
So their shameful car is going
それで彼らの恥ずべき車は行きます
smoke is invisible
煙は目に見えない
we taiwan
私たち台湾
I remember almost 20 years ago
20年近く前のことを思い出します
That explosive magazine has talked about this shameful car
あの爆発的な雑誌がこの恥ずべき車について話題にしました
But to this day, there is still no Taiwan
しかし今でも台湾は存在しない
then ask the professor
それから教授に聞いてください
Will there be superconducting cars in the future?
将来、超電導自動車は登場するのでしょうか？
Thanks
ありがとう
Japan is ready to build one
日本はそれを構築する準備ができています
from tokyo to i think it was osaka
東京から大阪だったと思います
This is already a national strategy
これはもう国家戦略だ
It's going to build this in 2025
2025年にこれを建設する予定です
superconducting car
超電導自動車
right
右
Of course it is not completely superconducting now
もちろん今は完全に超電導ではありません
i listen now
今聞いています
Sounds like it's not exactly hot tide
どうやら熱潮ではないようです
I said it also uses some low temperature tide
低温潮も使うって言ってた
it has some hybrid designs
いくつかのハイブリッドデザインがあります
Because all use high temperature tide
全て高温潮を使用するため
can be expensive now
今は高価になる可能性があります
too expensive
高すぎる
so it may now have a
したがって、現在は
But this cryogenic industry
しかし、この極低温産業は
It is Japan's century-old plan
それは日本の100年前の計画です
Japan now has
日本現在有個
Japan seems to like to make a hundred-year plan
日本は百年の計画を立てるのが好きなようだ
planning
計画
Then it has a big plan
それから大きな計画があります
cryogenic industry
極低温産業
become the most important industry in their country
彼らの国で最も重要な産業になる
What is cryogenic industry
極低温産業とは
That is, making many things is related to low temperature
つまり、多くのものを作ることは低温に関係しています
There are many benefits of low temperature
低温の利点はたくさんあります
So what are they going to do with these low temperature
それで、彼らはこの低温をどうするつもりですか
So build this superconducting train
それでこの超電導列車を造ってください
is the plan of one of its elephants
それはその象の一頭の計画です
so you just mentioned
それであなたは今言った
The high temperature tide guide and the low tide guide
高温潮汐ガイドと干潮ガイド
The cost of low temperature tidal conduction is much lower
低温の潮伝導コストははるかに低い
because it's been years
何年も経ったから
Done
終わり
Therefore, the trouble caused by high temperature tide is just mentioned
そのため、高潮によるトラブルは今述べた通りです。
That is, it is more fragile than it is a ceramic material
つまり、セラミック素材よりも壊れやすいのです。
OK, the other Mr. Lu, these are good materials
OK、もう一人のルーさん、これは良い資料です
It's easier to do, the same
やりやすいです、同じです
I mean those blue pill cakes
つまり、あの青い錠剤ケーキのことです
The ingredients of the blue medicine cake just mentioned are relatively easy to make
先ほど紹介した青いメディシンケーキの材料は比較的簡単に作れます。
less easy to consume
消費しにくい
Yes, it is not easy, because it is relatively flexible and flexible to make this kind of
はい、この種の作成は比較的柔軟で柔軟であるため、簡単ではありません。
You know the cable, you say you can bend it
あなたはケーブルを知っています、あなたはそれを曲げることができると言います
It's broken after a bend, it's okay
曲げたら壊れた、大丈夫
That electric current is incredible, so it absolutely cannot happen
あの電流はすごいから絶対にありえない
When doing this kind of thing is the most difficult to apply
この種のことを行う場合、適用するのが最も困難です
safety is the most important
安全が最も重要です
But security is
しかし、セキュリティというのは、
Many problems with shooting are not physical problems
撮影に関する多くの問題は物理的な問題ではありません
It's about mechanics and engineering.
機械や工学の話です。
that's hard
それは難しいです
So why did he only do one kilometer for so many years?
では、なぜ彼は長年にわたって 1 キロしか走らなかったのでしょうか?
The long is what you want to do so long
長くやりたいことは長いことだ
pull such a long line
こんなに長い列を引く
Everyone you can bend, right?
誰でも曲げることができますよね？
The cable can't be bent
ケーブルは曲げられない
It must be able to bend, right?
きっと曲がるはずですよね？
then you will be fine
そうすれば大丈夫です
that is difficult
それは難しいです
Of course they've been improving and you can see that.
もちろん、彼らは改善しており、それがわかります。
These countries are doing their best
これらの国は頑張っている
always improving
常に改善している
Because this is a big industry
大きな産業だから
Who can do it? It's a very good job, of course.
誰がそれをできるでしょうか? もちろん、それはとても良い仕事です。
whoever has a very big industry
非常に大きな産業を持っている人は誰でも
this is no problem
これは問題ありません
so this is what they do
これが彼らのやっていることです
Taiwan does not have this aspect
台湾にはそういう側面がない
thank you professor thank you
ありがとう、教授、ありがとう
I would like to ask you, Professor, what you just said
先生、今おっしゃったことをお聞きしたいのですが
CurvePair is electronics and childbirth
CurvePair はエレクトロニクスと出産です
Its interaction causes overrun to
その相互作用によりオーバーランが発生し、
but my problem is
しかし私の問題は
When you use a single or a single cooling down to 1K 2K
シングルまたはシングルを使用して1K 2Kまで冷却する場合
At this time, giving birth should be
このとき、出産はこうあるべきです
Your Ginger should not vibrate
ジンジャーは振動してはいけません
That is, childbirth should be fixed there.
つまり、出産はそこで固定されるべきです。
I just can't
できない
Just understanding is how the electronics interact with the child at this time
現時点で電子機器がどのように子供と相互作用するかを理解するだけです
This is what I just said
これは私が今言ったことです
absolute temperature zero
絶対温度ゼロ
The atoms and ions will still oscillate
原子やイオンは振動し続けます
this is quantum mechanics
これは量子力学です
Otherwise, the uncertainty principle is violated
そうしないと、不確定性原理に違反します
We all know the uncertainty principle
不確定性原理は誰もが知っています
is that you must never have a thing
それは、決して物を持ってはいけないということです
my position
私の立場
The position of space is immobile
空間の位置は不動である
because if you don't move at all
なぜなら、まったく動かなければ
The kinetic energy of that thing is infinite
その物の運動エネルギーは無限です
unlimited
無限
is impossible
不可能です
so it must move
だから動かなければならない
will definitely move
間違いなく動くだろう
So why is superconductivity so difficult to say?
では、なぜ超電導を言うのがこれほど難しいのでしょうか?
That is, it is all related to quantum mechanics
つまり、それはすべて量子力学に関連しています
It's all about quantum mechanics
すべては量子力学に関するものです
Classical mechanics is completely inexplicable
古典力学はまったく説明できない
Of course it was 1911 and no one wanted to appreciate
もちろん、それは 1911 年であり、誰も感謝しようとはしませんでした
After I understand quantum mechanics, I want to say
量子力学を理解した上で言いたいのは、
This is a full quantum
これはフルクォンタムです
Then you just said it will still move
じゃあまだ動くって言ったじゃないか
you can't keep it from moving
それを動かさないようにすることはできません
this is impossible
不可能だよ
So this shock is bound to happen
だからこの衝撃は必ず起こる
That's how it is
そういうことです
this is
これは
he sounds bad
彼は悪く聞こえる
Actually it's his benefit
実際、それは彼の利益です
There are so many strange phenomena
不思議な現象がたくさんあります
If it could happen in the quantum world
それが量子の世界で起こり得るとしたら
These strange phenomena will all appear
これらの奇妙な現象はすべて現れます
He has a new statement
彼は新たな声明を発表した
Not the usual world we are familiar with
私たちがよく知っている普通の世界ではありません
No
いいえ
Can
できる
The teacher just mentioned superconductivity
先生は今超電導について言及しました
we take the battery away
バッテリーを取り外します
The current will still run inside
電流はまだ内部に流れます
May I ask if this situation is impossible?
この状況は不可能なのかどうか聞いてもいいですか？
have what
何がある
That is to say, I made a machine
つまり、機械を作りました
I don't need to attack its energy
そのエネルギーを攻撃する必要はない
it can work forever
それは永遠に働くことができます
But the current you just said keeps running
でも今あなたが言った流れは流れ続ける
it sounds like this
このように聞こえます
that's because
それは
this is here
ここにあります
because this is here
ここにあるから
It can manipulate state, it can use
状態を操作したり、使用したりできます
You can't talk about motivation
モチベーションについて語ることはできない
If you use the motivation to say that you still want to use this
まだこれを使いたいという動機を使えば
if you put this, this, this
これ、これ、これを入れたら
The flywheel just mentioned is
今言ったフライホイールは、
It's done now
これで完了です
Just steer it around
ただ操縦してください
The purpose of its rotation is to transfer kinetic energy
回転の目的は運動エネルギーを伝達することです
Because rotation is kinetic energy
回転は運動エネルギーですから
put energy in
エネルギーを注ぎ込む
that can store a lot of energy
たくさんのエネルギーを蓄えることができる
Because it depends on the volume and shape of your work
作品の量や形状により異なりますので、
can be very big
とても大きくなる可能性があります
Then you put it in, how do you take it out?
入れたらどうやって取り出すの？
Then you have to connect to another thing
次に、別のものに接続する必要があります
it will turn slower and slower
それはますます遅くなります
Because energy is conserved
エネルギーが保存されるから
no motivation
モチベーションがない
There is something wrong with this word
この言葉には何か問題があります
This is not a motive here
これはここでの動機ではありません
Its energy is also conserved
エネルギーも保存される
Then if you take it off, it's gone
じゃあ外したらなくなるよ
OK, this is
OK、これは
Energy is always in balance
エネルギーは常にバランスが取れています
OK, energy will never come out when you are empty
そう、空っぽではエネルギーは出てこないのです。
There are several laws in this physics
この物理学にはいくつかの法則があります
without exception
例外なく
I would like to ask, does the current definition of superconductivity mean that its resistance must be zero?
そこでお聞きしたいのですが、現在の超電導の定義では抵抗が0でなければならないということなのでしょうか？
Or when you said the number of degrees in the data just now?
それとも、先ほどデータの度数を言いましたか？
Its resistivity also has a value, what does that mean?
抵抗率にも値がありますが、それは何を意味しますか?
No, it has value in Siwenhao, but it has no value below a certain TCE, it is 0
いいえ、Siwenhao には値がありますが、特定の TCE 以下では値がありません。0 です。
The so-called superconducting train used in Japan also uses this phenomenon of reaching zero to let...
日本で使われているいわゆる超電導電車も、このゼロになる現象を利用して...
That's right, what you saw just now is the high-temperature superconductor here, and the spirited one floated up just now
そう、あなたが今見たのはここにある高温超電導体で、さっき浮き上がった元気なものです
It is superconducting there. A few pieces of superconducting material here had a resistance of 0 at that time.
そこは超電導で、ここにある数個の超電導物質は当時抵抗が0でした。
That must be 0, that is, as I just said, it must be 0
それは 0 でなければなりません、つまり、今言ったように 0 でなければなりません。
Then if it is not 0, that thing will be taken soon, it will not run for so long
それが 0 でない場合、それはすぐに取得され、それほど長くは実行されません
It's just because of its metal, right, you... you need to get the battery
それは金属のせいですよね、電池を手に入れる必要があります
It will have this man named Eddie Curran, which is what I just said
そこにはエディ・カランという名前の男が登場することになる、それが今言ったことだ
It's gone in no time
あっという間になくなってしまった
If you want to keep adding a lot
大量に追加し続けたい場合
A lot of your hands will be hot
多くの手は熱くなります
Because the metal will be hot
金属は熱くなるので
They all turn into resistors and dissipate energy.
それらはすべて抵抗器に変わり、エネルギーを消費します。
but not here
でもここではない
it just keeps running
それはただ走り続けます
The only thing that didn't end up was because it evaporated
結局終わらなかったのは蒸発したからだけ
take this liquid
この液体を取ります
but evaporated
しかし蒸発した
it's not too early
まだ早すぎません
it warmed up
暖かくなりました
That's why the price stopped
だから値段が止まったんだ
but the question just asked
しかし、今尋ねられた質問は
if i seal it up
私がそれを封印したら
It's fine if it's sealed well
しっかり密閉されていれば大丈夫です
Now there are many laboratories
今では研究室がたくさんあります
These liquids are all sealed.
これらの液体はすべて密封されています。
so it's been inside
だからそれは中にあった
it doesn't evaporate
蒸発しない
that can be a long time
それは長い時間になるかもしれない
then there is no such problem
それならそんな問題はない
So why save energy
では、なぜエネルギーを節約するのでしょうか
Why do they think this is energy saving
なぜ彼らはこれが省エネだと考えるのでしょうか
It saves electricity compared to usual current trains
通常の電車に比べて節電になります
there is a reason
理由があります
You just need to close it up
ただ閉じればいいだけです
It's not that hard when the machine arrives
機械が到着したら、それほど難しいことではありません
you don't have to do it again
もう一度やる必要はありません
don't add oil
油を加えないでください
Oil sells nothing
石油は何も売れない
then ask again
それからもう一度質問してください
When the current of this material runs with zero resistance
この材料の場合に流れる電流が抵抗ゼロの場合
Is there any damage or consumption of this material?
この素材に損傷や消耗はありますか?
No
いいえ
as far as i know no
私の知る限りではありません
because it doesn't hit anything
何も当たらないから
No, you and I don't have resistors
いいえ、あなたも私も抵抗者を持っていません
so it didn't hit the good stuff
だから良いことは起こらなかった
no way to consume it
それを消費する方法はありません
ok, is there any more
はい、もうありますか
But theoretically no
しかし、理論的にはノーです
Of course I don't know what your question is
もちろんあなたの質問が何なのか分かりません
After your engineer
エンジニアのその後
it must still have some condition
まだ何らかの条件があるはずです
it's better
それは良いです
the only thing is
唯一のことは
Yes, the only thing is in transform energy conversion
そう、変換エネルギー変換だけです
Switch from this to another time
今回から別の時間に切り替える
There may be some energy savings there will be
多少のエネルギー節約はあるかもしれない
Because you're not everything manipulative
あなたはすべてを操作できるわけではないから
No
いいえ
Because usually when the energy conversion
なぜなら、通常、エネルギーが変換されるとき、
You need to convert this energy
このエネルギーを変換する必要があります
Energy summoned into another energy
エネルギーが別のエネルギーに呼び出される
into electric energy or into mk
電気エネルギーまたはmkに
Of course you will have some provincial numbers
もちろん、州の番号もいくつかあります
Energy summoning is like burning gasoline to become a machine leader
エネルギーの召喚は、マシンのリーダーになるためにガソリンを燃やすようなものです
You won't be 100% efficient
100％効率的になることはありません
The problem with this energy call
このエネルギー呼び出しの問題点
But it itself has no province number energy
しかし、それ自体には州番号エネルギーはありません
But when you use it or facilitate it
しかし、それを使用したり促進したりすると、
Of course there will be some energy provinces
もちろんエネルギー州もいくつかあるだろう
it's inevitable
それは避けられない
I want to ask the teacher
先生に聞きたいのですが
Is Ci Fu superconducting?
Ci Fu は超電導ですか?
Or is it like the one from Shanghai Cifu?
それとも上海慈富のようなものですか？
Is it still a type of superconductor?
やはり超伝導体の一種なのでしょうか？
Yes, but it doesn't have to be superconducting
はい、でも超電導である必要はありません
that's what i just said
それが私が今言ったことです
first time i show that
初めてそれを見せた
That is, you usually take a metal
つまり、通常は金属を摂取します
Take a magnetist's back and go back
磁力師の背中を借りて戻って行こう
In fact, there will be inverse
実際にはその逆もあるでしょう
you will
あなたはするであろう
if you are strong enough
あなたが十分に強いなら
you'll feel it resist
あなたはそれが抵抗するのを感じるでしょう
just be kind
ただ親切にしてください
so which two
それでどっちの2つ
It is equal to South Pole to South Pole
南極から南極に等しい
North Pole to North Pole can float
北極から北極まで浮くことができます
But this thing is not very stable, just like what I said just now, it is not very stable,
しかし、これはあまり安定していません、先ほど言ったように、あまり安定していません、
Because you have to face it just right, and if you tilt it a little bit, you will be in trouble, and the trouble will be reversed.
ちょうどいい方向を向かないといけないし、ちょっと傾けると大変なことになるし、苦労が逆転するからです。
It's not very stable, but you can't do it without instability, stability is the most important thing.
あまり安定しているわけではありませんが、不安定なくしてはできません。安定が最も重要です。
So I just said that another group repaired your superconducting hair, and it has the magnetic flux of the magnetic field line locked inside.
それで、別のグループがあなたの超電導髪を修復したと言いましたが、その髪には磁力線の磁束が閉じ込められています。
So it is equivalent to having a thread inside, clamping it, so it is very stable,
内部にネジを入れてクランプしているのと同じなので、非常に安定しており、
Like the magnet just now, you can see that it is very stable, very stable, and if you look carefully, it is very stable, very stable,
先ほどの磁石のように、非常に安定していることがわかります、非常に安定しています、よく見ると、非常に安定しています、非常に安定しています、
You can drill like this by yourself, right? It drills, you can see that it follows the magnetic force line,
こんな穴あけは自分でもできますよね? 穴あけすると、磁力線に沿って掘っていくのがわかりますが、
It flew out without drilling that day, of course not so fast, but it can be seen that it drilled along this way,
その日は掘削せずに飛び立ちました、もちろんそれほど速くはありませんでしたが、このように沿って掘削したことがわかります、
That's very strange, isn't it? People don't have a track, and it's nothing. Why does it drill along this?
それはとても奇妙ですよね?人々は線路を持っていませんし、何もありません。なぜこれに沿って掘削するのでしょうか?
Then if there is a superconducting train in the future, it will be safer than a running train.
そうすると将来超電導列車ができたら、走っている列車よりも安全になるでしょう。
Superconductivity is also a kind of surrender
超電導も一種の降伏である
But wouldn't superconductivity be safer?
しかし、超電導の方が安全ではないでしょうか？
More power saving, is it safer?
もっと節電すれば安全？
But if it's more than 500 kilometers, I hope it's safe
でも500キロ以上なら安全だといいけど
they are going to try now
彼らは今から試してみようとしている
so why would they do it
それでなぜ彼らはそれをするのでしょうか
I just saw that Japan was trying to make a one-kilometer-long
日本が長さ1キロメートルの橋を作ろうとしているのを見ました。
have been trying for a long time
長い間努力してきた
This kilometer-long superconducting train
全長1キロメートルの超電導列車
right ? that of course is to try
そうですか？それはもちろん試してみることです
Many are engineering problems
多くはエンジニアリング上の問題です
Actually speaking, many of those things are projects.
実際のところ、それらの多くはプロジェクトです。
Of course, one is the issue of price, the other is the issue of engineering
もちろん、1 つは価格の問題、もう 1 つはエンジニアリングの問題です。
Now mainly these two issues
さて、主にこの 2 つの問題
I think it's probably technically resolved.
おそらく技術的には解決されていると思います。
Because they also make cables, America makes so many cables
ケーブルも作っているので、アメリカは非常に多くのケーブルを作っています
Also trying to test this problem
この問題もテストしようとしています
That is to say, everything else is a supporting engineering problem now.
つまり、他のすべては現在、サポートするエンジニアリングの問題です。
is more important
の方が重要です
Then the cost of this suit and the cost of superconductivity
それでは、このスーツのコストと超電導のコストは
superconductor is more expensive
超電導体のほうが高価です
Superconductors are now more expensive
現在超導比較貴
Yes, this high-temperature superconductor is of course more expensive to manufacture now
はい、この高温超電導体は、もちろん現在では製造コストが高くなります。
Of course it's also because he doesn't have mass production.
もちろん量産できないからでもありますが。
Wait until they progress to mass production
量産に進むまで待つ
Of course it's different
もちろん違います
this is totally different
これは全く違います
Of course countries are competing
もちろん各国は競争している
So the cost is the same for large quantities
したがって、大量の場合でもコストは同じです
right
右
The advantage is that the film energy saves a lot
利点は、フィルムのエネルギーを大幅に節約できることです
that's not noisy
それはうるさくない
he floated
彼は浮かんだ
that's fast, right?
それは速いですよね？
not noisy
騒がしくない
no sound
無音
Of course it's good, right?
もちろん良いですよね？
If it is floating in front
手前に浮かんでいる場合
I think it must be very comfortable to sit on
とても座り心地が良いと思います
I was wondering right?
私は疑問に思っていましたよね？
I sat in the one in Beishang
私は北昌の席に座りました
That's not bad
悪くない
Of course he wasn't fast enough.
もちろん、彼は十分な速さではありませんでした。
all at once
一斉に
but that's fine
でもそれでいいよ
that floats is a good thing
浮くのは良いことだ
You said that it will be faster if you overtake it in the future
将来追い越せたら早くなるって言ってた
will be faster
より速くなります
certainly
そうです
Of course
もちろん
Will
意思
Technology is improving every day
テクノロジーは日々進歩しています
good last step
良い最後のステップ
Teacher, you just said that
先生、さっきそう言いましたね
Energy conversion consumes energy
エネルギー変換にはエネルギーが消費されます
But just now you have experienced so much
でも今、あなたはたくさんのことを経験しました
The electrons are swapped again, this and that
また電子が入れ替わって あれこれ
Then you said they were dancing together as a metaphor
それからあなたは彼らが比喩として一緒に踊っていると言いました
dancing is tiring
ダンスは疲れる
Then why do they change their own words?
では、なぜ彼らは自分の言葉を変えるのでしょうか？
Doesn't seem to consume energy
エネルギーを消費していないようです
No, this is the look of this super old lady
いや、これがこのスーパーおばちゃんの姿だ
It's not an exchange to exchange energy
エネルギーを交換する交換ではない
Because your electron is here, right?
あなたの電子がここにあるからですよね？
Then when I actually exchange like this
では実際にこのようにやりとりしてみると
when you swap with your neighbor
隣人と交換するとき
You don't imagine it's tiring for you
それが自分にとって疲れることだとは思っていないでしょう
You have to change the chair with him, right?
彼と椅子を交換しなければなりませんね？
But I just said that for electronics
でも、私はエレクトロニクスについて言っただけです
He will be tired if he doesn't change
変わらないと彼は疲れてしまうだろう
Because of this Helenberg Uncertainty Principle
このヘレンベルグ不確定性原理のため
On the contrary, it is very comfortable
逆にとても快適です
The more you change, the better
変化すればするほど良くなる
So electrons in quantum teraroots
つまり、量子テラルートの電子は
Our usual thinking is wrong
私たちの普段の考え方は間違っています
because in quantum too
なぜなら量子でも
he is not sure
他不確定
That's how the uncertainty principle in mechanics sounds
力学における不確定性原理はそのように聞こえる
usually very simple
通常は非常に単純です
In fact, the impact of the uncertainty principle is very far-reaching.
実際、不確実性原理の影響は非常に広範囲に及びます。
this is
これは
Of course we don't know why nature
もちろん、自然がなぜそうなるのかはわかりません。
uncertainty principle
不確定性原理
But it obviously has this principle
しかし、明らかにこの原則があります
And that's what you just said
そしてそれがあなたが今言ったことです
it gets better and better
どんどん良くなっていきます
It doesn't like it and stays there
それが気に入らずそこに留まる
is high energy
高エネルギーです
so it won't happen
だからそんなことは起こらないよ
in the real material
本物の素材で
this won't happen
これは起こらないでしょう
unless you have great strength
よほどの力が無い限り
hold it hard
しっかり持ちなさい
that's what i just said
それが私が今言ったことです
then it won't exceed
それなら超えないよ
Then this can't be helped
それなら仕方ないですね
Otherwise, it's best to change
それ以外の場合は変更するのが最善です
good i think
良いと思います
director
監督
I just said that everyone is
みんなそうだって言っただけだよ
this is very well prepared
これは非常によく準備されています
Then I worked hard
それから頑張った
this
これ
take a very difficult question
とても難しい質問に答える
and let everyone know at least a little bit about
そして、少なくとも少しはみんなに知らせてください
I am also very grateful to these two students
二人の生徒たちにも本当に感謝しています
this i just saw that
これは今見たところです
The barrel of the liquid bomb is there
液体爆弾の銃身はそこにある
That's a heavy thing to move here
ここに移動するのは大変なことだ
move all the props
すべての小道具を移動します
I just hope you can get some
いくつか手に入れられることを願うばかりです
At least some knowledge
少なくともある程度の知識は
This achieves the purpose of our knowledge miss
これにより、ナレッジミスの目的が達成されます
Well, we are very grateful to Li Xiugang
そうですね、李秀剛さんにとても感謝しています